Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening and good good day
everybody and uh welcome to episode 339
of the Ask Abijit Show. We are back.
This is the weekend and I hope you're
all doing very well and we're going to
discuss the ongoing events in the war
that is ongoing in Iran, in West Asia
and maybe other topics as well. Before
we get into all of that, let us see who
all is there on the live stream live
with all of us this fine evening this
fine day. Any vari
good evening ma'am good good morning
ma'am. Uh Mochi Exo Gaming, Geopolitical
Dubai is here from Indor. Good to see
you sir. Shri Ramachandra Mahapraam. Uh
Kanesh Koshik Radhir Radh Aush Pande
Push Singha Kind Taku Kindo Taku Vitri
Vitri Martinez Adwit Ashwani
uh who else? Rohan Bid Mataram Cosmic
Observer Sachin Yadav Alkashikari
Namaste Aayush Pandy once again. Uh who
else do we have? Um
uh Dur Panchchal
from Deutsland. Good to see you. Uh
who else? Who else? Uh, Mochi Gaming,
Durat
Panchal, Aayush Singh, Pranam
online sir, ultimate power A1,
Opuspicious Jinx, Sumit, Sumit, Agaral,
Bonjour, Reflex Maybe um, Study Vlogs,
Bhuvanendra, Upad, Upada, Satiendra,
Abhishek, Shugla Live, Swami is also
here. Good evening. Uh
Chahak Jatani Amitrit Singh
uh Suga Sugant BKS
reflex maybe Chahak Jatani once again
Kindotaku SKR7733
is here from New York Israel okay New
York Israel that's interesting Shivam
Karan Nalawad Jamir Salanki Rahul Nay
hello Abishek live from Kpur U Shivam
once again v one Suganta BBK is once
again G Karthikan wise idiot
uh Anup Anup is also here Sam Prammanic
reflects maybe Aayush Pande by Singh
General Subai Somi is here from Jaipur
Kindu Vijay Vagila good morning General
Subai once again Priyanis Om Vijay Ujual
Duta hello Durat Panchchal hello Karnawa
Jam Anant
uh reflex maybe study vlog Hogs
Sai Kiran Shiv Kapoor Ashish Noise Jatin
Shukla is here from Jabalpur. Good to
see you. Uh Pra Sad Dalal
Alan J Alan J Victor is here from Oman.
Well, I hope you're doing okay. Oman
Blitzkrieg is also here. Ankit Ram Ram
Da Da
Da is here. Sumit Agarwal, Ishwar, Somi,
Frostster, Pratar Dhana, Namaskar,
yes, Wolfpack Nation, Critz 278.
Um, and everyone else. Arjan, Skyland,
hello. Jay, Guman, hello. Sonakshi Gupta
is here from Jalander, good to have you
ma'am. Anikit Bachwan, Bachwani, Jatadi,
Pratik Parajuli, hello and everybody
else. Okay. So, let's go. Let's uh
discuss what is happening. So before I
get into the Q&A which we will obviously
do let's see let's quickly take a look
at what's happening right now in the war
I mean what's the latest that we have
let's see there's questions about what's
happening do you remember Trump used to
keep saying that India during operation
Sindur India has lost what four five six
seven god knows how many aircraft right
he used to keep on pointing that out I
mean claiming making all kind all all
kinds of claims well Five American
refueling planes have been struck and
damaged at Prince Sultan Air Base in
Saudi Arabia according to a WSJ Wall
Street Journal report. So
five aircraft have been struck and
damaged. Damaged means destroyed.
They're gone. Another one was destroyed
over Iraq and uh we don't know what
happened to its crew. And uh uh we we
had three aircraft, three American
fighter planes being shot down over
Kuwait. So I don't know how many
aircraft have been destroyed American
aircraft but things are not going well
for the United Nations. Surya says this
is what too much winning looks like.
Yeah. So yeah that that's one thing
that's happened. Now we have this from
Trump. Trump says and this is a while
ago. Yeah. This is this happened a few
hours ago like 12 15 hours ago. Uh Kir
Island has been obliterated. Moments ago
at my direction, the US Central Command
executed one of the most powerful
bombing raids in the history of the
Middle East and totally obliterated
every military target in Iran's crown
jewel, Kir Island. Well, as far as I
know, there was no military targets
there. It was oil infrastructure. So,
that's been taken out. Um, Iran has no
ability to defend anything that we want
to attack. There is nothing they can do
about it. That's what Trump cla Trump
claims. Iran's military and all all
others involved with this terrorist
regime according to him would be wise to
lay down their arms and save what's left
of their country which isn't much. So
that was that is what Donald Trump says.
He says that the US has destroyed Kir
Island. So that's another escalation.
Things are not calming down. Things are
escalating.
Trump I think he's hellbent on dragging
the entire world into this matter.
Essentially, it means he wants to set
off World War II, it looks like. And now
we have this statement,
this tweet from the Prime Minister of
Israel's Twitter account that was posted
and then a few minutes later it was
deleted. Official statement from the
Israeli Prime Minister's office. Rumors
circulating on social media about Prime
Minister Benju bin Netanyahu's status
are unconfirmed.
We urge citizens to rely on verified
updates. Efforts are underway to
establish contact and Prime Minister
Netanyahu remains committed to Israel
security.
So the Prime Minister's office, the
official account tweeted this then
deleted it sometime later. It said that
the rumors are unconfirmed and efforts
are underway to establish contact.
I'm sorry. Establish contact with whom?
With Prime Minister Netanyahu.
So is the Isra
say was it saying that there was no
contact with Prime Minister Netanyahu?
Is that what they were trying to say and
then they deleted this?
This is extremely extremely
confusing concerning for the people of
Israel
and looks like something is up.
Looks like there was no communication or
contact with the prime minister of
Israel, Mr. Mr. Netanyahu. And then they
deleted this.
So So the question is where is Netanyahu
now? Where is he? has something happened
to the prime minister of Israel and
that's what the rumors are all all about
on social media right now. There's a lot
of speculation happening. So as far as I
am concerned I don't make any statements
until there is official verification of
whatever. So when uh there was this
rumor there were these rumors about
whether Mr. Kame is alive or dead I did
not say anything about it. It's only
after the government of Iran officially
reported that he had been assassinated.
That's when I said that he is dead.
When it comes to Israel, right now it
looks like we don't know whether he's
alive or not.
This statement
is actually adding fuel to the fire.
It actually said that the efforts were
underway to establish contact with Prime
Minister Netanyahu which implies that
there was no contact with him at this at
this time when this was tweeted. This is
9:42 a.m.
uh sorry P.M. yesterday which is about
10 and what 22 hours ago and after that
we have no idea what's happened to him
and uh there is this statement that's
come out from a person from from an
Israeli account what's it say the
Israeli people are grappling with
significant challenges today there are
reports of changes in the senior levels
in the levels of senior leadership in
addition to an unexpected event and
Benjamin Netanyahu has left his position
permanently
so this This is from early morning today
and now obviously this is speculation.
We don't have any official confirmation
of whether this um this is true or not
but yeah so right now we don't know if
Netanyahu is alive or not. If he is
alive is he is he in good health? Is he
injured? What's the situation?
So big question about Netanyahu right
now. Big question mark over Netanyahu.
So this is a well an important
development I would say.
in the war and right now we don't know
what the situation is. So, we're going
to keep an eye on this. So, the war
isn't going the way Trump wants. The war
is going very poorly for Trump. It's
going very poorly for Israel as well.
It's of course going very poorly for
Iran, too. Iran is getting hit and
hammered.
The damage that Iran is taking is it's
going to cost probably trillions of
dollars to repair. So, Iran is taking
tremendous damage. I don't know how many
Iranian civilians are being affected and
in what way obviously in the worst way
one can imagine when there's bombing
happening
right so this is a disaster and the Gulf
states
the nations in the Gulf region whether
it's Saudi Arabia it's UAE it's Oman
it's Qatar it's Bahrain it's Kuwait
and the other nations well their
economies are in a are in a mess the
state of Hormones remains closed
It remains closed.
The UAE's economic model is is in
tremendous jeopardy. The Dubai economic
model is in is under tremendous stress.
People are leaving Dubai.
Yeah. It's it's in absolute disaster if
you are Dubai, if you are UAE, if you
are the other nations in the region.
And this this is this has happened
because Trump and Netanyahu dragged the
entire region into the war. And whatever
they were hoping to achieve, none of
that has been achieved.
Iran is fighting. It's going to it's
going to take tremendous damage. But
they are they are okay with it. They are
saying, "Okay." And and even if Trump
tries to end the war, Iran will not want
to end the war. Iran will want to ensure
that every single American military base
in the region is permanently destroyed.
and America's power projection
capabilities in the region are reduced
to zero.
If if Iran accepts a ceasefire right
now, what will it what what's going to
be the effect of that? The Americans and
Israelis will take 2 three years to
regroup and then they will eventually
launch another another attack on on
Iran. So Iran wants to end this matter
once and for all. Now, even if Trump
tries to do back channel negotiations
through intermediaries and ask for a
ceasefire, it's not going to happen.
This war is going to last now.
It's going to last. This war is not
ending anytime soon.
Absolute disaster these people have
dragged the world into and it affects
everybody including us. It includes the
people of India and the people of China
and the people of Japan, the people of
the entire world.
That's the situation. What else is
happening?
Now, this is not about the Iran war, but
look at this.
India has something called the Navic
system. It's the Indian version of GPS.
So, the So, look, the Chinese have BU,
which is their version of GPS. It's it's
a constellation of satellites that
provide positional navigation.
So if you have a phone or whatever, if
you are driving a car, you can use the
Chinese buu system to replace GPS
wherever you are in the world. It's a
global system. It's a global
constellation of satellites. The Chinese
have the Russians have Glonas, their own
constellation of satellites that provide
the same service around the world.
There's a European system as well. And
there's the American GPS which is the OG
like like you would like like you would
say it's the original grade system GPS
global positioning service. Now India
has Navic
and the Navic system provides such
services positioning positioning
services satellite navigation services
in the Indian subcontinent. India is a
low ambition nation. So our the the the
Navic service its coverage is is
restricted to the Indian subcontinent.
And now and and you see why Navic was
created because during the Cargill war
when India needed GPS to properly target
the Pakistani positions the Americans
switched off GPS for India for the
Indian military. So the Indian military
was suddenly left without
the global the the satellite positioning
and navigation service which means the
effect of that is that we could not
accurately target the Pakistani
positions
and therefore India created Navik.
Now what's the status of Navic today?
So India's homegrown Navic network built
after the 1999 999 Cargill conflict to
avoid foreign GPS dependence now runs
only on on just three satellites for
full positioning, navigation and timing
services. IRNSS1F
launched in 2016
and passed its 10-year life has already
lost two clocks and now only handles
oneway disaster alerts which means it's
not useful anymore. uh and the other sat
and the other satellites they also I
mean I don't know whether they're
functional or not and essentially you
need at least four satellites to be
fully functional for this service to be
operational and now we only have three
satellites most of the atomic clocks
which were foreign clocks have failed
okay and now there is there are plans of
newer Navic satellites but I don't know
when they will be launched and you had
PSLV rocket failures and all so right
now India is without India India is left
without
its Navic service. So if there is
operation Synindur, if there is a war
with Pakistan, the Americans will the
Americans support Pakistan, right? The
Americans support Pakistan. So they will
not offer they will switch off the GPS
services for the Indian military and now
we won't have Navik
that is the situation right now. So did
the government of India not see this
coming that this satellite has a 10 year
lifespan and maybe you know when 2 three
years are left we should launch new
satellites and maybe a couple of the
rocket launches failed so so make plans
accordingly when you are planning for
something you should plan that you know
possibly some rocket launches will fail
something will go wrong so you should
have backups
so I don't know what the government of
India has been doing with the space
program I have been speaking about this
for a long time that we are completely
neglecting the space program and the
applications the military applications
and so on but today we are in a
situation where we don't have our own
positioning our own satellite
positioning service
I'm not sure when the replacement
satellites are going to be launched 2026
sometime maybe end of the year so right
now we can't fight a war I mean we can
fight a war but we are left blind we
don't have the satellite positioning
excuse me we don't have the satellite
positioning positioning service anymore
What what do you make of this?
I mean when you are the government of
India, don't you plan for these things?
I have been a longtime supporter of the
government of India. I still support the
government of India. Of course, it's our
government. But this has to be called
out. This is a disaster.
I don't care what the problems are.
This has this this is unacceptable.
unacceptable.
So right now the Indian military does
not have this global satellite
positioning service. It either relies on
American GPS.
I don't know if Russia will offer GLONAS
to India but that is a possibility.
Russia and India have very close
strategic relations. So but the point is
we should not have to rely on foreign
services.
We should have our own service. We have
the scientists. We have the the
engineers. We have ISRO. We know how to
build these satellites. Why was this not
planned properly?
Absolute disaster.
Yeah. And is this how you become
superpower?
We are not even a local power now when
it comes to this this problem.
H extremely disappointing. So this is
this is kind of what's going on the
world going on in the world right now.
uh the Iran war it's it's going to drag
on now
the United States is doing very poorly
we don't know if Netanyahu is alive or
not
uh and we have issues closer to home and
the the straight of hormones closer Iran
has given India permission to have to
have Indian vessels transit the straight
of hormones apparently some Indian
warships are going to the region uh to
escort these warship these oil tankers
and gas u tankers if necessary and so
And so that's what's going on. But the
United States is losing this war. Israel
is losing this war.
It's not losing in the sense that it's
the US is losing. It's losing in the
sense that it has not been able to
achieve any of the objectives they
wanted to achieve. They have day one
Trump said that we're going to do a
regime change. That's had that's not
happened at all.
They said that we want to make sure that
Iran's nuclear program is permanently
ended. Trump claimed it ended
permanently last year. Now again, they
want to end it permanently. That's not
working out. They want to destroy Iran's
missiles and drones. That's not going to
work out at all.
And Iran is now going to dictate terms
in this region, including
to the neighboring nations. And the
neighboring nations can't rely on the US
anymore for military protection.
which has failed miserably. So that is
the situation in this war right now
and it's going to be an extended
conflict and some some powers are going
to
will benefit from this and some nations
are going to be weakened as a
consequence of this. As a consequence of
this, America's our projection
capability in West Asia is declining.
It's dwindling. If this continues for 6
months, it's going to go down to zero.
This war could be the beginning of the
visible decline of the United States,
geopolit geopolitical decline of the US.
So that's where we are. Okay. Uh that's
enough of the update. We can discuss a
lot more dur when I take the questions.
So let's see what questions we have
today.
Um first question is by Agni Vanam. Gita
says truth always prevails. Why do you
contradict? I mean what
what what does this have to do with the
war?
Gita says see first of all satya jayata
is truth always prevails right it that's
not in the gita that's not from the
bhagat gita it's from from the manduki
opanishad right um it's it's uh not from
the bhagat gita it is from what it is
from the
mundakaishad munda upishad
um and look
why do I say that why do I contradict
this okay let Let me explain to you as
if you are 80 years old. Let us say you
are a Bangladeshi who has entered India
illegally. What is the truth that you
are an illegal infiltrator who has
entered India illegally
but you have acquired Indian
documentation. You have an Indian
Aadhaar card. You have an some other
Indian documents.
You may even acquire passport. Then
these documents which are genuine Indian
government issued documents
they will position you as an Indian
citizen even though the truth is that
you are a foreign infiltrator.
So doesn't falsehood prevail in this
case? Aren't there millions of
Bangladesh like this in India? What
happened to Satya Jay then? Okay, I'm
explaining to you as if you're 8 years
old.
Another example, we know that Iraq did
not have any weapons of mass
destruction. Saddam Hussein did not have
any weapons of mass destruction. And yet
the Americans claimed that Iraq has
WMDs. Saddam has WMDs. And they invaded
Iraq and destroyed Iraq completely. And
later they said, "Oh, no, no, no. We
made a mistake. There were no WMDs." But
the deed was done. Iraq was destroyed.
Who won? Did truth win or did the
falsehood win? Falsehood won. Another
example.
I'm explaining as if you're 8 years old.
We know that Tibet is not China. We know
that Tibet has never been part of China.
The Tibetans are not Chinese people.
Their culture is not Chinese culture.
Now open the map of the world. What do
you see?
What is prevailing? The map of the world
shows Tibet as part of China. Is truth
has truth prevailed or falsehood
prevailed? Shall I give you 78 more
examples? Maybe you will understand then
or let's move on. All right. Okay.
Mary Kane, good evening ma'am says uh
nuclear you mean small modular modular
reactors. Uh I'm not sure if I have
discussed uh small modular reactors.
Um not sure what the context is. Uh
there there is something called small
modular reactors which are small nuclear
reactors with a small amount of fuel and
then they produce this these reactors
produce heat which can drive a steam
engine steam turbine and produce
electricity and maybe that's the future
of nuclear reactors. Instead of having
gi gigantic huge nuclear reactors you
can have small modular reactors that can
power maybe uh a village or a small town
or maybe an industrial area or
something. So those are small modular
reactors and uh these small modular
reactors are also pretty expensive. They
cost I mean the the the the cost of such
reactors is in the billions of dollars.
Uh I'm not sure of if Iran has small
modular reactors. So the the concern
that the west has with Iran is that it
has a nuclear weapons program. So uh I'm
not sure what the context is but that's
what small modular reactors are. That's
you know that's the future perhaps of
nuclear reactors but uh yeah okay Kesh
Koshik says Jamar how Sudashan Chakra
air defense will operate um not sure I'm
not sure Sudashan Chakra air defense is
is it some new development I am not
aware sorry
Anuj
Anuja thank you
um Anuja once again says I am using a
stroggy a soggy straw to save the
planet. Yeah,
we all try our best to reduce our carbon
footprint and uh be more environment
friendly and you have this war going on
where billions of tons of of of uh of
petroleum are being burnt, right? Yeah.
Shoubham says, Shubam Chip says, "Can
you explain petro dollar? What is it?
How it works?" See the petro dollar
system
it it doesn't mean that the dollar is
made of petroleum.
Okay. What is this this concept right?
So uh in 1944 there was something called
the Bretonwoods conference and in this
conference it was decided that going
forward from 1944 onwards the US dollar
will be used as the world's reserve
currency and the US dollar was backed up
by gold at the time. So it was it was on
the gold standard. So if if the US
printed a certain amount of money, it
would print that amount of money only if
had it had that much amount that much
amount of gold in its reserves. So that
went on until 1971. In 1971, I it was 71
like 70 or 71. That's when Richard Nixon
u you know delin the US dollar from the
gold from the gold standard which means
that the US could from that point
onwards just print American dollars
without having gold in reserve. Okay.
And the status of the dollar would be
enforced through military might.
So the dollar would remain the global
reserve currency and everybody would be
made to trade internationally only in
dollars and this would be enforced
militarily without actually backing up
the US dollar with gold. And then at the
same time around the same time they
reached an agreement with the uh oil
producing nations, oil exporting nations
like Saudi Arabia etc. that whatever
transactions they would do with other
countries selling and buying oil, they
would do these transactions only in the
US dollar. So oil would be sold and
bought only using US dollars. No other
currencies, no Chinese yuan, no Russian
ruble, no Indian rupee, no nothing. Only
US dollars. So that is the petro dollar
concept that internationally
oil and petroleum it's only the
transactions are supposed to be only in
US dollars and this was backed up by
American military might. So that ensured
that nobody would dare transact do no
oil transactions purchases and sales in
any currency except the US dollar. So
that's the petro dollar system and
that's how it works. It works through
military might. The US enforces through
this through military might and that
essentially ensures that the US dollar
remains the most powerful currency in
the world. It has a genuine value and if
it has a genu genuine value that makes
the US uh economy the world's most
powerful economy
and the US has been taking the fullest
advantage of that. They have issued
treasury bonds. So it's a piece of paper
that other countries can buy. So let's
say you have a treasury bond of $100.
It's a piece of paper on which it says
$100 with some nice artwork and all
that. And let's say I am India. I buy a
$100 treasury note of the US. To buy it,
I have to pay the US government a 100
actual dollars, right? So by printing
these these pieces of paper, the
Americans
uh they acquire debt. So let's say China
purchases purchases a bunch of American
treasury bonds. Let's say a billion
dollars worth of Treasury bonds. So they
actually pay a billion dollars to the
US. And why is this a good idea to
purchase these bonds? Because the US
dollar is valuable and these bonds they
their their value appreciates over time.
So let's say I buy a $100 bond today. In
three years it may be worth $120, maybe
$130, right? as long as the US economy
is healthy and so on. So the Americans
by issuing paper pieces of paper they
actually are able to acquire real wealth
wealth and so on. So that's how lots of
nations acquire American debt. They see
it as an investment but now nations are
offloading the debt. So essentially the
petro dollar coming back to the petro
dollar system it's all about the
enforcement of the purchase and sale of
petroleum and oil only in US dollars.
Now that that control is slipping away,
the Saudis have been uh um selling oil
to China
and and uh taking money in in Chinese
yuan, not in in US dollars. So that is
the petro dollar system slipping away,
right?
Prattana says one Indian journalist uses
the term terror regime for Iran. Yes,
true.
One Indian journalist
uses this term terror regime for Iran.
So tell me when Dr. J Shankar
has discussions with the foreign
minister of Iran, is the Indian foreign
minister having discussions with a
terrorist?
When the prime minister of India day
before yesterday night spoke with the
president of Iran, Mr. Masu the Pesashki
was the prime minister of India talking
to a terrorist.
India
and Iran have been cooperating on on
various fronts, multiple fronts. We were
using the port of Chavahar, operating
the port of Chabahar at least some
terminals
u to uh send shipments of goods to
Afghanistan. So was India
cooperating with a terrorist nation?
India and Iran were working together to
ensure the safety and security and
survival of Armenia. So was India
cooperating with a terrorist nation to
save Armenia?
Has Iran ever launched a single terror
attack on India?
these Indian journalists who use such
terms I strongly I don't know who it may
be okay I'm not taking anybody's name
but I suspect that they
they are in some shape form or or form
in some manner potentially
hypothetically compromised whoever they
may be.
Yeah.
Why would you want to
to further the agenda of some other
nation?
If you are a journalist, why don't you
report factually and serve your own
nation?
I don't I don't get this. Yeah.
I don't I don't know who these
journalists may or may not be, but it's
very disappointing.
And I'm glad people are noticing now.
I'm glad people are noticing.
Vinit Pi, thank you very much. Vin G
Sergeant Skylan says India Iran seems
okay. Is our sovereignty still intact?
Okay. Two questions. Uh one question,
one observation. So India, Iran seems
okay. Means the relationship, right?
Yeah, the relationship seems okay.
Um let's see. Give me a second. There's
something the Iranian
who tweeted that. Give me a second,
please. Okay. Give me a second. Give me
a second. Give me a second. Um, who was
it that tweeted something? Give me a
second. I I'll need to dig it out before
I can put it on the screen.
Um, so it's about the India Iran
relationship obviously.
Uh, the Iranian foreign minister tweeted
this or who tweeted this? Who tweeted
this? Okay. Okay. Let's let's put this
on the screen.
So this is the foreign minister of the
Republic of Iran. Uh Mr. Say Abbas
Arachi. Okay, this is what Mr. Arachi
tweeted. The US spent months let's let's
put it here. Okay. The US spent months
on bullying India into ending oil
imports from Russia. After two weeks of
war with Iran, the White House is now
begging the world including India to buy
Russian crude. Europe thought that by
that backing illegal war on Iran would
win US support against Russia. Pathetic,
right? So yeah, that's that's what the
Iranian foreign minister has tweeted.
But yeah, and and what he's saying is
obviously
well it it obviously could have some
some factuality to it. Some perhaps
some. So India and Iran are talking. Uh
the Indian foreign minister had multiple
discussions on the phone on m on more
than one occasion with the foreign
minister of Iran.
Uh the government of Iran has issued
multiple statements about u the these
conversations and they are pretty clear
that India is a valuable partner for
them.
So when the war started and the supreme
leader Mr. Kam of Iran was assassinated.
Uh the Indian prime minister did not say
a word about it. Right. And the Indian
prime minister tweeted on multiple
occasions condemning the so-called
violations of sovereignty of the Gulf
nations obviously by Iran. So at that
time clearly India was taking the side
of the US and Israel in the first two
three days of the war. clearly obviously
openly
but verbally India was not not taking
any actions that would hurt Iran but
verbally the prime minister of India was
you could say leaning towards the US and
and Israel
then India recalibrated
if you see the last four five livereams
of mine you can see this this transition
happening in the titles of my live
streams ask 334 onwards you will see
that there's a change happening first
India takes a side. India picks a side
then India recalibrates. So how did
India recalibrate? India the India's
foreign secretary Mr. Misri he visited
the Iranian embassy and he signed the
condolence book officially expressing
India's condolences over the
assassination of Mr. Kamei. Right? Then
the Indian foreign minister speaks with
spoke on multiple occasions with the
Iranian foreign minister. Then last
night or day before yesterday night, Mr.
Modi spoke with Iran's president
and Iran has said that it will allow
Indian
vessels or vessels, oil tankers that are
going to India to cross the straight of
Hormuz. So Iran is making an exception
for India, Russia, China. India, Russia,
China, right? For for the transit of oil
through the straight of Hormuz. So Iran
is not treating India as one of the
coalition members who are attacking it.
India Iran is treating India as as a
valuable partner right now. So yeah the
relationship seems okay. I think the
government of Iran understands that
India is under pressure that India faces
all these constraints that India you
like they say hypothetically he's being
bullied by the Americans and so on and
India has made sure that India also gave
refuge to an Italian ship in in on on in
an Indian port I think Kochi right um so
India has taken actions that you could
see that Americans would call pro-Iran
but India's words initially look like
they are anti-Iran but actions always
trump words. So that is the situation
right? Is our sovereignty still intact
that I will look into once this war ends
or maybe in a month or so? Right now I
think India is is not uh India is taking
striking a more more or less neutral
note in this matter. India is not
allowing American ships to to dock at
Indian ports for refueling and
resupplying. That's not happening. The
Americans will definitely want that but
it's not happening which is good. India
has given refuge to an Iranian warship
in an Indian port which the Americans
could say is a hostile act against
America. So overall India is trending
straight. It's it's not there must be
pressure behind the scenes that we are
not aware of but India is not bending
and and caving into American demands. So
thus far I would say India is doing a
very good job of navigating this
extremely difficult situation.
Kakashi says why India today invites
Laura Loomer racist. It's a okay Laura
Loomer is is this lady who is on Twitter
and she has in the past said all kinds
of racist things about India and India
today invited her for some kind of uh
event major public event which happened
today I believe. Um so is this a good
idea? Is it a bad idea?
I think you know what if somebody has
been anti-India in the past and if we
invite that person over here that person
will most likely change their views
because we gave we invited them to that
person to a big event and we gave them
we treated them well gave them respect.
I think their their uh position may
change as a consequence. I think India
should we should stop being super
emotional
about these matters. Even if somebody
has been an enemy in the past, if by
if by giving them an olive branch we can
make them change their views and become
more positively inclined towards India.
Uh what is wrong in that? Right?
There's no harm in doing that. So I
don't think it's a bad idea.
There are lots of racist people in the
world.
If you see the tourists who come to
India, especially American tourists and
all, many of them are super racist. They
they they have these very disparaging
positions and opinions about India. But
typically if they spend a week or so in
India, they go back with a changed
approach and attitude.
Right?
So I think we should do more of this.
invite people who are kind of
anti-India.
See, there's a difference being between
being verbally anti-India and being
actually taking actions doing taking
steps that are that are nonverbally
anti-India. For example, if you have
somebody who writes anti-India books, if
you have somebody who who writes books
that that distort Indian history and are
Hindu phobic and and and so on, those
people should not be invited to India.
But somebody who's tweeted stupid things
if by inviting them to India they they
become positively inclined towards India
I think it's a win
and there are people who run these NOS's
and all
in the US that supply funds to
anti-India activities and all those
people you should not invite so the
people who take actions who have who
have a record past record track record
of anti-India activities
should be blacklisted but people who
have been let's say stupid saying stupid
things about India and they are
prominent people if you bring them to
India invite them give them nice
treatment and they become pro- India I
think that's okay I'm fine with that
okay Vive Singh says considering the
disaster in Gulf do you see an
opportunity for great Nicobar project to
become a success as UAE and maybe in the
future Singapore will be in trouble well
I hope Singapore is not in trouble for
any reason uh the UAE see this uh this
uh trans shshipment port that we are
constructing in great nicobar
uh it will be a success no matter what
happens and even if it's not a major
international success it will be
successful for India because it's going
to you know reduce significantly the
pressure on Columbbo which is a Sri
Lankan port so right now see it's it's a
geographical matter you see let's let's
see the map and we let's understand why
this is important for us even if we
don't if we even if we disregard the war
that's happening see right now what
happens is that there is a lot of
traffic that happens
uh between the Mediterranean Sea and
East Asia. So all the shipment that
happens comes through the Swiss canal
here. Okay. It it crosses the uh Red
Sea. Then it uh transits the straight of
Bab al-Mandde and then it goes down
south into the Indian Ocean and then
enters uh this this this uh straight the
Malaka straight. And if these shipping
uh vessels want to offload some uh cargo
for India
that will be offloaded in Colbo and then
from Columbbo there will be other Indian
ships or maybe Sri Lankan ships or
whatever that will take all all that all
those goods to India. So Columbbo port
gets a lot of trans shshipment fees
which are unnecessary.
So now what we do is that we have the
we're going to have this port great
nicobar port right this is the island of
great nicobar so in that case it's an
Indian port uh at which all all these
shipments will be offloaded and from
there it can be then sent to India so I
think that's going to be a success
irrespective of what happens in this
disastrous war in the Gulf region right
so it's not that that that UAE and
Singapore have to fail for great nicot
to be a success. Great nicobar is a
great idea. It's very important. It's
already a very important project and
irrespective of whether anything fails
or not, it's going to be successful for
us.
Okay. Hyphen says,
I started a science fact shorts channel,
not this one. I didn't super chat from
it so it wouldn't seem like promotion.
It's doing well and I'm applying what I
learned from you. Thank you. Well, I'm
very glad. I'm very glad and I'm happy
that you're doing this. I like people
who take initiative and do things. So,
I'm glad you're doing this. I'm glad
it's doing well and I don't mind if you
post a super chat from that that account
as well. It's fine. No issues, right?
So, I'm very glad that that it's doing
well. Good job. I'm very glad and and I
hope that you keep posting over there
and I hope it's a great success. Thank
you sir. All the best. Do well.
Such sati sati says your opinion on the
artimus program. They've canceled the
lunar gateway space station which seemed
pointless anyway. Is it because of of US
bureaucracy?
Uh what was this lunar gateway space
station? Is it was it supposed to be a
space station in orbit around the moon?
which doesn't seem like a good idea
anyway to me. What's the point of that?
Let me let me quickly uh find out what
what that is. Okay, what is this? Lunar
Gateway Space Station. Give me a second.
Lunar Gateway Space Station. Let's
Google that. Lunar Gateway Space
Station. What was this thing? It's a
planned Yeah, exactly like I thought. A
planned international modular space
station orbiting the moon.
So, has it been cancelled?
Has it been cancelled? Let's see what
does Wikipedia have to say about this.
Would be a space station assembled, etc.
It was intended to be, etc. Criticism,
potential cancellation,
so proposed cancelelling this thing, big
beautiful bill, etc. So, looks like it
may not see the light of day. And it
doesn't make a lot of sense to have a
space station orbiting the moon. Just go
straight to the moon, right? The lunar
surface. Why do you need a space station
orbiting the moon? I'm not really sure.
Uh the Aremis program, what's my
opinion? I think um it's a good
initiative if you are American, right? U
it's been decades since you had American
boots on the ground on the moon and uh
they're going back to the moon. Now they
have much better rockets and they're
going to be able to send many a lot more
people and a lot more material to the
moon and now we have a much better
understanding
of the moon as compared to the 1970s and
1980s. We know that there's a lot of
water on the moon which means that we
don't have to transport a tremendous
amount of water from the earth to the
moon. You just have to land near the
south pole and go to those to those
craters, those permanently shadowed
craters where you have massive amounts
of water which are known to be there and
you can use that water uh for sustenance
and for whatever else you need need
water for. So I so we have a much better
understanding of the moon today
and obviously now that you have multiple
pro countries with with significant uh
significantly advanced space programs
there's going to be sooner or later a
situation where countries start marking
off territory as their own on the moon
and the s the earlier you reach the moon
the more of a chance you have to do
this. So if you have multiple habitat
habitations on the moon, multiple bases
on the moon, you can start creating a
city there and then you can say it's our
sovereign territory. The Americans
Americans will definitely do this. The
Chinese will do it. The Russians also
may reach the moon sooner or later. I
have no idea about India 2030, 2040
whenever humans will set Indian people
will set foot on the moon. I'm not sure.
Uh but yeah, whatever. So I think
Artemis makes sense geopolitically and
from a scientific perspective also.
Yeah. Uh, lunar gateway doesn't make any
sense anyway. Yeah.
Kakashi says Arachi on X insinuated that
the US successfully bullied India into
stopping buying Russian oil and Peshkan
did not tweet about Modi call like his
calls with Putin and Sharif. It is what
it is.
Uh once again let me go to that uh tweet
by Arachi.
Did he say that? Let's see. Once again,
Ragi
um
what did Ragi say? So Raki says that the
US spent months on bullying India into
ending oil imports from Russia. Well,
that's not entirely factually true
because India did not end its oil
imports from Russia. India reduced its
oil imports from Russia and then the
Americans claimed that India had ended
oil imports from Russia. So not entirely
factually correct. India reduced its oil
imports from Russia but did not end
them.
But Trump claimed and the Americans
claimed that India had ended oil imports
and the Americans then claimed that we
have given India temporarily permission
to start importing oil again from
Russia. So the Americans kept claiming
that uh India has stopped buying Russian
oil. The data shows that India had kept
buying Russian oil but reduced quantity.
So Arachi will say what he will say and
Arachi is basing whatever he is saying
on what the Americans have been
claiming. Right? And Peskan did not
tweet about Modi like his calls with
Putin and Sharif. That's fine. That's
okay. That's his choice.
That's all right. But look at the
actions they are allowing Indian oil
destined for India to pass through this
trade of Hormuz
and overall the relationship seems okay.
Obviously there's going to be strain
there's going to be a strain in the
relationship
because of the war
but overall India is India the India
Iran relationship is okay. So Iran is
not taking any actions that are
anti-India. India is also not taking any
actions that are anti-Iran.
Now all these words and diplomacy that's
okay that is fine.
Achara Chanaka says will the FDI flowing
to Dubai shift to Singapore or India?
That remains to be seen. Look if you
want FDI to flow into India you have to
lay down a ra red carpet for the FDI for
the investors.
You have to make the investors feel
welcome. How do you make somebody feel
welcome? You give them great treatment.
You treat them like they are royalty.
You open doors for them. You don't ask
them to fill this form in triplicate and
do this 78 different procedures and then
wait 3 years to acquire land or 7 years
to acquire land. You don't do all that.
You have to make them feel welcome.
So if you don't make if India doesn't
make it easier to invest in India, then
the FDI flowing into Dubai will go
somewhere else. Not to not to India,
maybe Singapore, maybe somewhere else.
If you see it's not FDI that's flowing
into Dubai. It's wealthy people who go
to Dubai mostly
and invest in some FDI foreign direct
investment. Yeah. Invest in real estate
re invest in whatever.
So why can't India do that? Why can't
India make make investors feel welcome?
So unless we do that nothing will flow
into India.
Abai Singh says what do you think is the
timeline for Indo-China war? I don't say
any indoor Indochina war. No timeline.
Mighty Air says why a gourjs were called
criminal tribes.
We never called anybody criminal tribes.
The godamned British called certain
people criminal tribes.
Okay. Why? Because they resisted the
British occupation of India.
That's why they were called criminal
tribes.
See,
before the British came to India,
nobody was called a criminal tri. I
don't know, we will disregard what the
what the muggles and the Turks may have
done. They also did all kinds of nasty
stuff to reconfigure Indian society.
But when the British started taking over
large parts of India, various
people resisted that in various parts of
India and those who kept resisting were
then categorized as criminal tribes and
then it was made a criminal offense
to have any kind of relationship with
them. This caused the marginalization of
those communities.
That's what happened. So, so if if some
people were classified as criminal
tribes, it's because they resisted the
British occupation of India.
Vive Singh says, "Navic issue is
serious. When the fact that we are going
to have unmanned water and air drones
which will depend on such satellites for
navigation and data links, it's very
serious.
If you want to have unmanned drones
that will in a war strike at enemy
targets within enemy territory, if you
want to have such systems, you need to
have your own navigation system,
satellite navigation system.
And now we don't have a functional
satellite navigation system. It is not
serious. It's a disaster.
How did the government
end up in this position?
How did they let things slip so badly?
I I simply have no answers. I can't even
imagine how
this is acceptable,
right? I I just don't understand.
If you have a advanced missile that that
takes data that takes you know that that
takes inputs from satellites to
fine-tune and refine
its position so that it strikes the
target exactly where it's supposed to
strike
then you need that system right the
Navic system what should happen
is that in the next 3 to 5 years India
should create a global satellite
navigation system not a local one. Maybe
it'll take 30, 35, 40 satellites,
maybe five for backup. Why can't we do
it?
How much does a satellite cost?
I mean, the entire Mongolan mission cost
$75 million including the rocket launch
and everything else. So, I would say a
Navic satellite may cost $10 million,
maybe $20 million.
Okay, maybe the atomic clock costs 10
million more. So maybe it's 30 million.
So if you have 10, it's 300 million. If
you have 30, it's 900 million.
So for let's say a billion billion and a
half dollars, you could have a global
navigation system
and let's say another 100 million for
the rocket launches or whatever. Why
can't we do it? What is preventing the
government of India from doing this? Why
uh is the government of India taking
this
so lightly?
So anyway, this is a disaster for India.
Absolute disaster.
Okay. Cosmic Observer. Thank you very
much sir or ma'am. Akshit Sharma says um
namaste. Why is the US why will the US
not try putting boots on the ground in
Iran? Uh to understand why the US will
not want to do this. Uh let us give me a
second. Do I have a relief map of Iran
somewhere?
Maybe I do. Okay. Maybe I do. Give me a
second. Let me put that on the screen.
All right. All right. Let me put the
Okay. So to understand
why the US will not do this, let's see
the relief map of Iran.
This is what Iran looks like. Okay, Iran
is a mountainous country. It's full of
mountains. The coastline of Iran is
super mountainous
and the borders of Iran are super
mountainous. The interior of Iran is
super mountainous. Mountains all over
the place. When you have terrain like
this, it's like the the entire country
becomes like a fortress. And if you're
trying to invade it, it's going to be
suicidal.
As an example, the Americans uh they
tried uh invading Afghanistan, right?
They they invaded Afghanistan
and they fought the Taliban for 20
years.
At the end, the Americans succeeded in
replacing the Taliban with the Taliban.
And the Americans, even though they may
have occupied Afghanistan for 20 years,
they were in possession of Kabul in a
few cities. They had no control over
what was happening in the countryside
and the mountains, in the valleys. The
Americans tried their best to defeat the
Taliban,
but they complete they they failed. They
utterly failed. Now, Iran is like
Afghanistan multiplied by 10 or maybe
multiplied by five or whatever.
It's going to be even more difficult and
the Iranian military has been preparing
for 40 years, 45 years.
It's going to be suicidal for the US to
try this.
Prataradana says even if Iran is totally
destroyed and bulcanized, it doesn't
guarantee attacks on GCC, US bases, etc.
Capability want to attack, won't go
away. I think even if Yeah, I agree with
you. Even if Iran is somehow destroyed,
balkcanized.
Okay. So
let's see the ethnic divisions in
Persia. Okay. To understand the
potential hypothetical bulcanization,
how it may happen. Okay. Um ethnic
groups in Persia.
What happened? One second. Ethnic groups
in Iran.
All right. Let's see. Let's see the map
of the ethnic groups in Iran. So, as you
can see, there's multiple ethnicities in
Iran. Maybe we'll look at this. Yeah.
So, red is Persian. In the east, you
have the Balois. Then you have
Loristanis and Kurds and uh Kurasani
Turks. You have the Azarbaijanis, Azaris
and so on and so forth. So even if Iran
is somewhat bulcanized, the majority of
the country will remain united because
it is portion. Balkcanization can only
happen on ethnic lines
if it ever happens. So even if it is
bulcanized, even if the Azari part of
Azarbaijani part of Iran is lost, even
if the uh
um Kuresh part of Iran, Kuresh, the
western Kuresh part of Iran is lost or
whatever Persia even if Baljasthan is
lost, more than half of Iran will remain
united and they will keep fighting.
they will keep fighting and they will
still have the capability
to hit US bases in the GCC countries and
so on. So it won't go away. So I agree
with your assessment. I agree.
Rumit misses. I think because India
wants to show west that we are executing
space missions on such a lower cost.
ISRO is compromising heavily on quality
of satellites. ISRO should get better
for the security of the nation.
So uh I don't want to speculate as to
why we have a space program. Are we
doing this because we want to impress
the world and show the west that we also
can do things the kind of things you do?
Why do we have ISRO? Why do we have a
space program? Is it to impress the
world? I don't know about that.
A space program costs money. It should
money should be invested but the
outcomes should
the the outcomes should strengthen the
nation. Why do we need a space program?
We need a space program first of all
because we need satellites in space. If
we have satellites in space, we can have
a global positioning system. We can have
eyes in space that look at what's
happening on the ground. We can have
satellites that are used for
agricultural research purposes. that
will help the farmers. We can have
satellites that are spy satellites,
military satellites. These things, if
you are a major nation, you need these
things. Eventually, we will want to have
a presence on the moon eventually on
Mars. Otherwise, other nations will take
over and we'll be left behind. So, for
these reasons, we need a space program.
Okay? That's why we need it. It's it's
vital to have have a have a world-class
space program. It should not exist
because hypothetically we we want to
impress the world. Who cares?
Now it's clear that the Indian space
program is being neglected by the
government.
How many rockets do we launch in a year?
Four, five, six. It's peanuts. SpaceX
launches
dozens of rockets in in in a month.
It's a private company.
Um,
so India needs to, the government of
India needs to take space seriously.
I've been saying this for years.
India needs to take this very seriously.
ISRO needs to
whatever issues may exist in ISRO. I
mean the issues may be administrative
and bureaucratic
rather than scientific or engineering
related.
The quality of the staff is great. The
engineers are great, the rocket
engineers and so on. The the issue
probably is potentially hypothetically
bureaucratic or or administrative. That
needs to be fixed. If there is any
sabotage potentially is happening which
is why PS rockets have failed at least
twice recently that needs to be fixed
addressed right so u yeah it's extremely
concerning that India the government of
India has completely taken space lightly
in the past few years yeah and this
needs to be addressed urgently
Don Thomas says do you actually think
democracy is the best solution we have
feels like a popularity contest all
together team with better PR comes to
power also our problem with meritocracy.
Well, democracy is actually see what is
democracy. It's it's a popularity
contest.
It's all about being popular. Now the
easiest way see when you have a
lowquality population with low IQs
because of the horrible education system
then you have to
then to be popular you have to do stupid
things.
You do do stupid things like making
people happy in the short term. Giving
people short-term benefits to get votes
immediately.
Short-term benefits like giving people
reservations. Give everybody
reservations to please everybody. give
everybody freebies. The Indian taxpayer
pays money and that money is taken to
give freebies to people. Oh, everybody
gets some if you are in a certain
community or if you if you are important
bank, we will give you free free money
every month or whatever gladly bha
yojana this yja that yojana free stuff
free money all that
we'll give you reservations even if you
score very poor marks we'll will you
will get an admission in medical college
or whatever that sort of thing. So this
is what democracy brings to you if you
have a lowquality population. So if you
want to have democracy, you need to have
a highquality intelligent population.
For that you need a high-quality
education system. India has one of the
world's worst education systems. India's
education system is trash. So democracy
can work potentially
if you have
a high quality, intelligent,
well-informed thinking population. India
doesn't have that.
India has a population that's all
emotions, emotions, no thinking.
no understanding of the world.
So for for a nation like India,
democracy doesn't work. Democracy is a
disaster. See what
what is leadership.
The purpose of democracy is to elect
leaders, right? Representatives, the
right person to represent you all and
lead your lead you. So let's say you are
a constituency a town or some portion of
a city and you vote for the Lok Sabha.
So you want to elect the best possible
person who will represent you and act as
your representative in Lok Sabha and
essentially that person will lead you.
You want the best possible person to
lead you. Now, as a leader, you are
supposed to have a long-term view
and to
make decisions that are going to be
beneficial for the people in the long
term, not short term.
But generally,
decisions that you make that will be
beneficial long term, those decisions
that invariably involve short-term pain.
decisions and actions that will give you
long-term benefits, they usually involve
short-term pain. But in a democracy, if
you give people short-term pain, you
lose your you lose the next election.
And that's why the nation is trapped in
this endless cycle
of giving people short-term pleasure
and that is going to sink the nation
in the long term.
A leader has to take unpopular
decisions.
But in a democracy, if you take
unpopular decisions, you lose the next
election. Which is why democracy is a
disaster for India. Subashandra Bos was
right.
If he had come to power in India, then
he wanted to impose dictatorship for 20
years to fix the problems and then bring
in democracy potentially. That was the
right solution. But we started with
democracy. People who don't know how to
read or write or think, they they vote.
It's like allowing an 8-year-old to
vote.
Somebody asked me in the beginning of
this live stream, right? Why do I say
that Satya J is wrong? So, I have to
explain as if that person is 8 years
old.
So, India's population, it's like a
bunch of it's like more than a billion
eight years 8y olds who are voting. They
don't understand the world.
They think the this their reactions are
all emotional reactions. When people
react emotionally to everything, imagine
what will happen when a leader takes a
decision that will give you short-term
pain. How will they react? They'll say
this, this is the worst leader we've
ever had. Vote him out of power.
Which is why for a nation like India,
democracy is a disaster. Disaster.
And even good leaders if they want to
remain in power they will have to start
making compromises.
Yeah.
Honey Guru says when did Islamic rule
begin? Muggal or DL sultanarat. But it
depends on which part of India we're
talking about. The muggal empire itself
during orang's time which was the
largest extent geographical extent of
the muggal empire. Even at that time it
did not encompass the entirety of India.
So if you were to ask me when did
Islamic or Turic rule begin in India? Uh
well it starts with uh in in the 8th
century with Muhammad bin Kasim uh
invading Sind and
and and occupying
some territories in Sind. That is the
beginning. So at that time what had
happened is that Persia had already
fallen to the Arabs. So the for the
first time the Arabs
could see India from Persia because west
of Persia you have India. Right now it's
temporarily Pakistan but that was India.
So then they said let's expand our
territory. So that's why Muhammad bin
Kasim made a raid or a series of raids
or whatever on Sind
and then captured some territory. That
is the beginning you could say. Apart
from that uh when did proper Turk rule
begin in some part of India? 1,000 years
ago when Gandhar fell to the Turks.
Gandhar means Afghanistan. That's where
it begins. And then slowly slowly it
crept ahead crept ahead. Gandhar fell to
the Turks 1,000 years ago.
And then you had the Delhi Sultanate
which was a small sultanate for a while
that happened like 300 or so years ago
or 300 or so years after the fall of
Gandhar. So in the meanwhile for
centuries India resisted and fought the
Turks off over and over and over again.
Then you have the establishment of the
Bir Sultteranet,
the Mamluk Sultan, right? The slave
slave Sultanate.
You had these these uh Mamluk kings like
uh Iltmish in Balban.
Ilutmish his daughter Razia was was
king. uh sorry queen of that region
small region for a while. So even at
that time the Delhi Sultanate was not a
big thing.
So if you want to say the ask about the
beginnings in the west it is Sind about
8th century in the 8th century in the
north north it is Gandhar about a
thousand years ago around 1,000 AD.
Mr. Sid says do you think if the US wins
this war radical Islamic terrorism will
take a huge blow probably the only
benefit for India? No, Islam. Sorry.
Iran is not a whatever you mean by
radical Islamic terrorism, Iran is not
that
Iran is not a radical Islamic terrorist
nation or whatever, it's not. So even if
the Americans win,
it won't have what you are saying is not
going to happen.
the if you consider something to be
so-called radical Islamic terrorism that
emanates out of Pakistan
not out of Iran.
Okay, please understand that. Let us not
fall prey to propaganda because what
happens if we fall prey to propaganda
then saty is no longer valid. then
then you have a situation where
so let us not fall prey to falsehoods
and propaganda
this terrorism it emanates out of
Pakistan
not Iran if the Americans hypothetically
win the war which they will not win but
even if they do Pakistan will remain a
terrorist entity and they will be
actually emboldened
and then you India will face way more of
of this phenomenon that you're talking
about. It's it's going to have the
opposite effect.
It the terrorism will not take a huge
blow. It will be emboldened.
All right.
Okay. Cosmic observer says, could the
deep state shift power to New Delhi?
Well, you know, even Xiinping could
hypothetically step shift power to New
Delhi, but no.
No. Okay. No. Answer to your question.
The answer to your question is no.
No, not not happening.
Sai says good evening sir. Yes, good
evening. I have two questions. What's up
with North Korea suddenly launching
missiles and saw this news piece where
which said that Iran allowed Indian
vessels to pass through the straight of
Hormos called India's friend. Maybe
India is playing this well. Okay. What's
up with first of all the question about
North Korea? What's up with North Korea
launching missiles? Well, North Korea is
doing this simply to remind the world, I
mean the US that if you have any uh
hopes or any any
uh if you are hoping that maybe if Iran
is not going well, we will target North
Korea or whatever, just remind you that
we have missiles that can reach the
American mainland.
So North Korea it keeps from time to
time it keeps on demonstrating its
military capabilities and operational
readiness
to its enemies. Its enemies are the US
and the US vasals in the region.
The US vasals in the region sadly are
North Korea are South Korea and Japan.
So North Korea periodically
de makes
a demonstration
of its missile capabilities,
technological capabilities and
operational readiness and that's that
that's what we have seen just now. It's
not suddenly happened. It's it it keeps
happening from time to time. Every few
months the North Koreans do this. So
that has the effect of first of all
reminding the world that North Korea is
not to be treated lightly. it has to be
taken seriously. Secondly, it it uh
keeps the army as a well welloiled
machine. It ensures that you know the
missiles are in good shape and so on and
they can keep testing and maybe they
they make some improvements to missiles
and they can test it out in that case.
So that's about North Korea. Now news
piece about Iran. Iran has allowed
Indian vessels to pass through the state
of Hormos. It has. Yes. And India Iran
called India as a friend. It did it did
call India as a friend. Maybe India is
playing this well. India now is playing
this well. Yes.
Also like I said if you if you see if
you
if you see my channel okay if you see
the titles of the past few live streams
you can see that shift happening in the
Indian perspective. See uh 13 days ago I
had this emergency episode because the
war suddenly you know exploded. The
Americans attacked Iran and killed
Kamei. Then
that was 13 days ago. 11 days ago my
title was Iran war escalates. India
picks a side. That is when India the
prime minister of India um from his
tweets you could say that he has
verbally picked a side the side of
Israel and the US. Then 9 days ago I the
the title is the war USI Israel Iran war
Iran hits back Trump trapped question
mark. Then 6 days ago India recalibrates
right. So India's position has changed
over time. India recalibrates which you
so I think overall India is doing fine.
India may have verbally taken the side
of Israel and the US but uh but India
has not taken any actions that are
anti-Iran. India has taken actions that
are actually kind of pro- Iran
especially allowing an Iranian warship
to dock at an Indian port
when the Americans actually want to
destroy that that warship. So India's I
think overall India is ensuring that it
doesn't tilt too much on any side
and that's the right uh approach from
India's perspective. India should not
pick a side. India should not be pro- US
and Israel. India should also not be
anti- US and anti-Israel. India should
not be pro- Iran. India should not
should also not be anti-Iran.
We have good relations with all these
actors with the US. I mean US we have
good relations historically the past 20
years but Trump has messed it up. It's
not our fault with Israel. We always had
the good good relationship the past 10
12 years with Iran. Well that's a very
ancient story but yeah since 1980 or so
we've had good relations with Iran
reasonably good relations with Iran. So
we should not mess any of this up. So I
think overall India is doing the right
thing.
Pratana says conspiracy theory. The
government is destroying Israel for the
west.
Well, I could not possibly comment about
this. I mean, what does India the
government of India gain by allowing
ISRO to
wither away? Yeah, sure. May the West
will be pleased if this happens. If Isra
becomes defunct or isro is starts doing
very poorly, the west will be pleased
about it. But uh why do we want to
please the west?
So um
yeah obviously so the the implications
of what you are saying I understand and
I hope that that is not the case. The
implications are that there are elements
in the Indian government that have been
bought out by the west. That's what
you're implying.
I hope that is not the not the case.
Yeah.
Pratip Kumaro is about Adele
and Aname. I have no idea what these
things are, but let me try and Google
that.
Adele,
what on earth is that? Adram and Aname.
Adele.
Oh.
uh Adra Male and Anamele were ancient
Mesopotamian deities worshiped by Sephar
white colonists resettled in Samaria as
described in something or the other
associated with the Assyrian city of
Supar. Their worship involved the
barbaric ritual of burning children in
fire.
Okay, I am not aware of this. So I I
don't know what to say. This is the
first time I'm hearing these names. I
don't I I have not studied the history
of this region. It's never interested me
too much. I mean I've studied history of
Mesopotamia etc. I studied the history
of the uh Assyrians
uh the Mesopotamians but not their gods
and not these barbaric rituals. Those
things I have no idea about. So okay,
Panchchar says Psalm Psalm 91 1112 says
he shall give his angels charge over
thee.
I strongly believe Donald J. Trump is
our guardian angel. Please explain sir.
You believe Donald J. Trump is your
guardian angel? Our our as in who? Who's
us?
Our guardian angel means us. But who is
the US that you're referring to? Are you
talking about the United States? Are you
American?
You've paid in rupees. So it doesn't
look like you're American. Are you
saying he Donald Trump is India's
guardian angel or the guardian angel of
the entire world? I would disagree very
strongly.
I would disagree very strongly about
that. Donald J. Trump is no one's
guardian angel. He is a force of
destruction.
And these biblical or whatever psalms, I
have no understanding of those.
Um, yeah. So, what can I explain about
this? I can't explain what I can't what
I don't understand and what I disagree
with. So, okay.
Alkashukari says, "Has has peace
mediations, peace peace talks ever
stopped any wars so far?
Have peace mediations, peace talks
stopped wars in the past? I'm sure it's
happened. Can I think of any? I mean I
am not a student of minor wars. I've
studied the history of the first and
second world wars. Those wars were not
ended through negotiations and and
mediations and all that.
Uh
when it comes to other wars,
other wars,
the Gulf War, the the first Iraq, the
first Iraq war, the the first oil war
did not end through mediations and
negotiations. The second oil war did not
end. The second Gulf War, Iraq war also
ended with an American victory.
I am not sure if that happens. I'm I'm
sure minor wars may have ended in the in
the past through negotiations and
mediations and all but overall no major
war has ended like this. Can't think of
any. India Pakistan wars.
Um IndiaPakistan wars are not major
global wars. 1948 there was a war
which ended. How did it end? It ended
because Nehu went to the United Nations
instead of taking back Kashmir the the P
which is now P that part of Kashmir. Uh
1965 it ended whichever way without
negotiations or whatever. 1971 ended
with a massive massive disaster for
Pakistan.
Uh 1998 Cargill war ended with India re
recovering its territory.
Um
operation Synindhur was a minor very
minor war even in the India Pakistan
context three-day war. It ended after
the Pakistanis called India in kind of
it ended whichever way probably because
Donald Trump intervened and there was
not mediation or negotiations. It was uh
threats.
Uh so yeah I can't think of any major
war that has ended because of negot
negotiations and mediations.
Argittal says, "Is this war reshaping
the Middle East power balance between
Iran
and the USIsrael block? Is this decline
of US superpower status? Will it help
India?"
Okay. Is this war reshaping the p the
power balance, the balance of power in
the Middle East between Iran and the US
Israel block? Very much.
Very much.
Look, officially, I don't know what the
Americans uh are saying in the official
news that's coming out. Unofficially, I
very strongly believe
that most of the American bases in the
region have been significantly damaged.
If there if this war continues for
another two weeks,
all the American bases in the region are
going to be destroyed completely by
Iran.
Okay?
If those bases are gone, then America
loses its power projection capabilities
in the region completely.
Completely loses it
and Iran becomes the major power in the
region.
Okay, Israel is also a major power in
the region. It still has its nuclear
deterrent,
but Israel has taken massive damage.
Okay, the media may not be showing it,
but I'm I'm pretty sure Israel has taken
a similar kind of similar kind of damage
that Iran has taken.
So
the balance of power in West Asia is
being reshaped in front of our eyes.
The myth of the American military
umbrella has been shattered.
Whenever the war ends, maybe in few
weeks, maybe in a few months, whenever
it ends, if Iran is still standing,
which looks like it will be,
then well, the Gulf nations will have no
choice but to stop relying on American
protection, the Gulf nations economies
will be totally reconfigured as a as a
consequence. So, what we are seeing is
the beginning of the visible decline of
America's superpower status. America
can still destroy much of Iran through
nuclear attacks, but Iran will still
keep fighting.
America can't defeat Iran. That's what
is very clear now. Even after even after
a few months, if Iran runs out of drones
and missiles, they will still keep
fighting and the Americans won't be able
to defeat them even if they put boots on
the ground. So, this is a major major
miscalculation by the US. It's a
disaster for the
for for for for America. It's a disaster
for Trump. He can keep tweeting whatever
he wants. But this is a massive failure
by the US. And
Israel also has taken huge blues and
Israel also can't defeat Iran.
Um
so yeah to answer your question now in
in brief the war is indeed reshaping the
balance of power in West Asia and this
is the beginning of the visible decline
of American superpower status. Will it
help India? Well if American power
declines see today what is the major
problem India faces? The major problem
that India faces today geopolitically is
America's containment policy towards
India. America is trying to contain
India. They are openly saying they will
not make the same mistake with India
that they made with China. Which means
we will we will not allow you in your
economy to grow.
We want to constrain you. We don't want
you to grow beyond a certain point.
We want to use you as a market. We want
you to be a vasal.
Now if American
power declines,
then it's going to be good for India.
India will have more options. So yes,
Pratib Kumar Roy says, "I recently found
out that our galaxy is revolving around
a massive black hole called Sagittarius
A star. It's Sagittarius A star and all
galaxies forming a cluster called Lan
Lania Lania supercluster moving towards
shapely supercluster space is huge." Uh
correct? Yes. So we have so our solar
system is in one of the arms of the
Milky Way galaxy. The Milky Way galaxy
is a spiral galaxy. What's a spiral
galaxy? What does it look like? Let's
take a look. Spiral galaxy.
So we can't really see what the Milky
Way is shaped like because we are inside
it. But a spiral galaxy typically looks
like this. Okay. A great example is
Andromeda, which is uh our closest
neighboring galaxy. But a spiral galaxy
typically looks like this. It has got
arms that look like a spiral. And the
sun, our solar system is is is in one of
these spiral arms. Okay. And at the
center of our galaxy,
we have a situation. Okay. Through
observations, we have seen that there's
a bunch of stars at the center of our
galaxy that are dancing around very fast
around some invisible object.
And based on the calculations of the
masses of the stars and the speeds and
all that, that invisible object has a
mass of several million times the mass
of our sun. And it's invisible and
clearly it's a super massive black hole
most likely. Okay. Um, so once again, go
here. Uh
Milky Way super massive black hole.
No. What is that? Why is it in Danagri?
Um so at the center of the Milky Way we
have this stars uh Milky Way stars.
Okay. So this is a sim this is a a
representation of the stars at the
center of galaxy of our galaxy and the
way they dance around this invisible
object. So we can't see the super
massive black hole but we can see the
stars moving around around it and if you
take uh images over like a couple of
decades you will see how the stars have
been moving around this thing and that's
why we know it's there. Now our galaxy
is one of trillions of galaxies in the
universe and in our local supercluster
is called the Lania supercluster and we
can look at that also. Lania super Lana
Lani Lana Lania. Yes. Yeah. So that's
kind of what it looks like. The red dot
is our Milky Way and all the other dots
are other galaxies and so on. So the
universe is massive, huge. It's huge
beyond our imagination.
Okay. Argabital says, "If US bases look
vulnerable in conflicts, could host
nations reconsider hosting them? And do
they realistically have the power to
remove US bases?"
Right.
Um the US bases, do they look vulnerable
in conflicts? It depends on where the US
bases are. So right now you have a bunch
of American bases in West Asia that have
been very significantly damaged clearly.
Some of them may have been completely
destroyed
and these bases were created in these
host nations
by giving the promise that by allowing
the Americans to host a base in your
territory, you are getting American
protection, American military
protection. So if somebody tries to hurt
you, this American military base will
protect you. That was a story that was
told to these Gulf nations. Well,
clearly that story has turned out to be
a lie. These American military bases
can't defend themselves. Forget about
defending the host nation.
So this situation only
exists where you have a more powerful
nation in the region. So American bases
typically encircle nations that the
Americans don't like. You have American
bases that kind of encircle Russia. You
have American military bases that
encircle Iran. You have American
military bases that encircle China. You
have bases around India also.
So
when you so so now in West Asia, we have
seen that American military bases can't
defend themselves and can't defend the
host nations. What about Japan and South
Korea? Both of these nations host more
than 100 American military bases each.
Japan has more than 130 American
military bases. Now why do have the
Americans put all these bases there?
Obviously with an eye on China.
Taiwan is also an American fortress,
military fortress.
So now the Chinese are looking at what's
happening in Iran and now it's very
clear how to defeat the Americans. You
need tremendous numbers of ballistic
missiles and drones. If you have the
quantity, you will be able to defeat the
Americans no matter what happens.
So the question now is now that we
understand this, will South Korea
reconsider hosting American military
bases? Will Japan reconsider hosting
American military bases? They may
reconsider, but do they have the power
to remove them? They don't. When Japan,
when you have a nation like Japan with
more than 130 American bases in its
territory and thousands, tens of
thousands of soldiers, how can they
remove them? They won't go. The
occupying force is more powerful than
the host nation. So, they can't remove
them.
Right? The Gulf nations may be in now in
a position to ask the Americans to leave
permanently
because now they can tell Iran that you
know what we don't want the American
business we asking them to leave and if
they don't leave pound them more pound
them more destroy them and the Americans
can't do a thing about that so the Gulf
nations now are in a position to ask the
Americans to leave and not come back but
Japan and North and South Korea are not
in that position. Taiwan is not in that
position.
Koshulk Kumar Shukla says should India
try to stay out of all wars and provide
it provide services to everyone like
Sweden does for banking how feasible it
is. India should provide services
provide services to everyone. So India
should provide services to the US to
Israel to Iran everybody. It doesn't
make sense.
India should definitely stay out of all
wars. Look this war that's happening we
didn't start it.
It's not our war. We we never wanted
this war. This war is bad for the people
in that region and it's bad for us too.
So India should stay out of this war.
India should not take a side. Right? And
uh should India provide services to
everyone? Let's say India provides
services to the Americans. What kind of
service could India provide?
One service the Americans will want
India to provide is allow the US Navy
to be resupplied from America from
Indian ports along the west coast of
India. There are various Indian ports on
the west coast of India. The Americans
will say allow our ships to dock there
and then we will fly cargo planes to
Indian airports with supplies and those
supplies we'll bring to the ports to
your ports Indian ports and we will
resupply our warships with that. If we
provide that service to America
we are taking a clear side in the war.
and Iran will then consider India to be
an enemy nation. Do you want that?
Why do why do you want that? And what
sort of service could we provide to
Iran? I'm not sure. So my point is when
there's a war going on, don't take don't
take sides and don't provide services to
anyone. Not a good idea.
Nihal Ratur says I have observed among
world Iran have one of the most smartl
lookinging smart looking very
smartlooking
fit witty poetic well-dressed and
visionary especially Mr. Say Abbas Ragi.
All right sir, thank you for sharing
your observation. All right.
Pratep Kumar Roy says I also read
somewhere that our universe is most
likely inside a massive black hole and
big bang is of actually formation of a
black hole also. What is the black hole
information paradox?
Look, it's a theory.
It's a theory that maybe the universe is
inside a black hole. A massive black
hole. Maybe we are inside a massive
black hole.
Um,
it's a theory. There's no evidence for
it.
We know that the universe is expanding.
If we are inside a black hole, how come
the universe is expanding? Is the black
hole also expanding? Do we see expanding
black holes anywhere? We don't see that.
So if black holes have a certain set of
properties
that are valid everywhere
then how does that make sense along with
the known observational evidence that
the the universe is expanding?
It doesn't fit together.
So that's one data point that that kind
of tells you that we are maybe not
inside a massive black hole.
Right? So it's it's not a fact. It's
it's a theory
and uh we we have evidence we have
observational evidence that kind of
refutes that theory. But it's still a
good thought experiment to have. I mean
what if we are actually inside a black
hole? If you have a black hole that's
large enough to contain our entire
universe, how would that situation look
like from a physics perspective based on
what we understand of the laws of
physics? It's a good thought experiment
and that's why physicists consider these
things, these possibilities. But uh
there are issues with this theory. Okay.
What's this black hole information
paradox?
Um
see
black holes
are known to have only three properties
from it's called the black hole you know
from the perspective of thermodynamics.
There is something called the no hair
theorem. Black holes have no hair. Hair
means details.
So from the perspective of from what we
understand of black holes. Any black
hole any black hole that you take
anywhere in the world that that you
observe, it can be described by only
three properties. You only need three
pieces of information to understand
everything about the black hole. Its
mass, its charge and its angular
momentum. What is angular momentum spin?
Is it off spin or is it leg spin? Is it
off spin? Is it leg spin? That's all you
need to know. So if you know the black
hole's mass, charge and angular
momentum, then you know everything about
the black hole.
That is
the best understanding we have of black
holes. Okay.
So if so does it mean but but when a
black hole absorbs matter material it's
absorbing charge. So we know that black
holes have possibly a little bit of
charge overall charge becomes neutral
inside a black hole mostly but it's also
absorbing other information. For example
if it's absorbing photons photons of
polarization
what happens to that information about
the photon polarization that went
inside? Is it destroyed?
So there's a lot of information that
goes inside the black hole which seems
to get destroyed by the black hole and
at the end of the day all we are left
with is mass, charge and angular
momentum. But information can be
destroyed. That's also what physics
tells us. So are black holes objects
that violate the laws of physics. So on
the one hand we have information theory
that says information can't be destroyed
and then on the other hand we have black
hole physics that says black holes have
only three properties.
So there's this paradox
that you can't have this and that
together.
So that's the black hole information
paradox.
Epic with Ana says, "What do you think
US economic and political situations
change after the war?"
Well, I don't see this war ending soon.
It is not in Iran's interest to end the
war soon. If you end the war now, it
will give the US and Israel time to
regroup. maybe two, three years,
reformulate a good, better strategy and
attack Iran again.
And if Iran stops the war right now,
agrees to a ceasefire, then the
Americans will rebuild their bases in
the region
in all the Gulf nations. So Iran doesn't
want to end the war right now. Iran
wants to finish the American presence in
the region once and for all. And Russia
will will help Iran in doing that. China
will help Iran in doing that. It's a
disaster for the US. So let's say
sometime the war ends
with not a US victory and if the US
doesn't win it means the US loses. If
the US loses this war in this region
that is going to be an absolute disaster
for Trump and for the Republican party
economically
there's going to be a disaster for the
US because the petro dollar system will
no longer work.
And Iran will ensure if it succeeds in
this war in surviving the war that now
going forward Iran and oil will not be
sold in US dollars. Iranian oil will be
sold to other countries. Even the Gulf
nations will be pressurized in accepting
other currencies
for oil. So it's going to be a disaster
for the petro dollar system. The world
will start dd dollar rising rapidly. As
a consequence, if the dollar becomes
weak, it's the American economy will
start crashing.
This is a much bigger disaster than what
we are seeing right now than what most
people are seeing right now. If Iran
prevails in this war is that could
herald the end of the petro dollar
system
and Gulf oil will then be sold in
Chinese yuan, Russian rubles, Indian
rupees. The Americans may still
pressurize India to only use dollars.
Maybe India can be pressurized, but the
Chinese can't be pressurized. The
Russians can't be pressurized,
right?
So, it's going to be a very big setback
for the American economy. And from a
political perspective, it's a disaster
for Trump. Trump is this is this has
been his worst decision. Right? So, most
likely Trump and the Republicans will
lose the midterm elections. Trump will
become a lame duck president who can't,
you know, pass any legislation
and uh
and yeah, economically it's it's a big
big setback for the Americans and things
are going to get worse,
you know, every as time goes forth as
time as time goes by.
A Kam Jot says, "Why are the Jews so far
ahead in winning Nobel prizes?" Well,
maybe they are very brilliant people.
Maybe the Jews are the most intelligent
and brilliant people in the world.
Possibly maybe that's why they win so
many Nobel prizes. That's a possibility.
Maybe maybe there's that.
Uh Anerut Kumar says can you tell us
about Raja Rahul the founder of Rahul
Pindi? Look um
I am
I don't know his history in great
detail. Baba Raal right.
So the story I mean a lot of his story
is is shrouded in legend. So we don't
know what the exact story is but yeah he
there he was a Rajput he was a warrior
and uh he fought the Turks in the Punjab
region and he fought them and defeated
them and and freed the region from Turk
occupation and rule and he founded a
city in what is now Punjab which is
named after him Rahul Pindi.
Eventually the Turks took took over the
region again. But that's the show story
in short. I don't know the the details
because of we don't know what is what is
legend and what's actually the actual
accurate history. So I am not very sure
about it. Okay. So that's in brief about
Rawal.
Pratep Kumar Roy says Andra Mle Bal and
Anamik real Mulok I I don't know. I am
not aware of this. Sorry.
Herman Baja says it's sad to see some
section of Indians don't understand
nuisance with respect to Iran. You mean
nuance nuances either either they are
looking as only Muslim nation or they
are biased peddling somebody else's
agenda. Can you list some for viewer?
List some what some agendas or some
biases. Look, I'll tell you how I see
this this matter. I don't know how how
other people see. I don't know what to
list.
Uh I'll tell you how I see this matter.
See,
ever since I have been discussing
geopolitics, there have been people who
have portrayed me in various ways. One
portrayal is that in that Abijit Chava
is very strongly pro-Russia.
Another portrayal is that I am very
strongly anti- US.
Another portrayal is I am very strongly
anti-West.
Another portrayal nowadays is that I am
somehow pro Iran.
The fact of the matter is that I am
neither of these things. I'm none of
these things. I am only pro- India.
I see whatever is happening in the world
from the perspective of the Indian
national interest.
I understand who is trying to constrain
India, who's trying to contain India,
who's trying to harm India in various
ways. I understand who's not trying to
harm India
and that's how I do my analysis. Now,
when it comes to this war that's going
on right now, Iran obviously is a Muslim
nation officially, Islamic Republic of
Iran,
but that's okay, right? Why can't we be
friends with Islamic nations? Mr. Modi
has established great relations between
India and various Gulf nations like
Saudi Arabia, like the UAE, like Oman.
We've also had good relations with with
Iran. So just because a nation has a
certain religion doesn't mean that it's
naturally an enemy of India, right?
Lots of Indians visit the UAE all the
time. Lots of Indians live in the Gulf
region in UAE. They have they've been
treated very well. There have been
issues in some countries like whatever
those are. We'll not name them here.
Right?
So, see the world is complex. It's full
of nuances. When the education system
destroys your intelligence, you don't
see that. You only see things in black
and white. And that's an issue. So
that's why you've got lots of Indians
who and and when you don't see nuance,
when you don't understand nuance, when
you don't appreciate the complexities
and nuances, that's when you become
super susceptible to prop propaganda,
black and white propaganda.
And there's going to be a bunch of
Indians who are either taken over by
propaganda or who are peddling
propaganda on someone else's behalf
possibly.
Uh I will not take anyone's names or
whatever, but it is what it is, right?
So my my point is look at the entire
situation from India's perspective from
the perspective of the Indian national
interest. What are India's interests in
the region? Do you understand those
interests? If you don't understand do
some research
and then ask yourself is this war
helping or harming India's interests? If
the US wins does it help India's
interests or does it harm India's
interests? If the US loses, does it help
India's interests or does it harm
India's interests?
And maybe there is maybe both situations
can in some way hurt India's interests
and also further India's interests. So
which which situation which scenario is
is more beneficial for India? Which
scenario is less beneficial for India?
You to see you have to understand this
in great detail in detail. Right? Um
yeah. So with India it's always like
this. Indians are very emotional.
Indians don't understand nuance. Indians
don't do deep analysis. Indians are very
susceptible to propaganda. And it's
overall not the fault of the Indian
population. It's the fault of the Indian
education system that hasn't prepared
Indians for the complexities of
international relations.
That's the problem.
Srijan, thank you very much. Sri Jan
Anerud Kumar says why does India have
diplomatic relations with irrelevant
nations like Lebanon, Malawi, Yemen,
Somalia, Finland etc. Isn't this a waste
of time, energy and resources? It is
not. It is not. No nation is relevant.
For example, one one relevance of small
nations when you are
in the United Nations, let's say you
want uh
you want to pass a resolution. Let's say
you want to pass a resolution to condemn
Pakistani terrorism
and let's say you don't have diplomatic
relations with 78 countries. Those 78
countries will either abstain or vote
against you.
Yeah, maybe you will say the UN
resolutions are irrelevant or whatever.
But there are times when they are
relevant. That's one thing. Other thing
is that there are many of these nations
even though they may be small or not
powerful they may have valuable
resources
that may be useful for India
right and maybe if we don't have
relations with them maybe our enemies
will make relations with them and and
acquire those resources
so it is very important for a nation if
you are irrelevant if you are weak you
don't need to have relations with with
everybody but if you aspire to be a
superpower at vishuv guru or even a
great power or even a regional for then
it is very important for you to have
relations with everybody.
Okay, that's why India does this.
Raman Gil says do you think if World War
II broke out all these western Canada,
USA will countries could use Indian
diaspora as force recruitment for army
just like Russia?
Um if World War II breaks out, well this
this looks like the beginning of World
War II right now. First of all, let's
define World War II. World War II means
a war in which
a a large number of important in major
countries get embroiled. Okay. So if
this war continues
and if the Americans drag European
nations into this, they force European
nations to start participating
that will force Russia and China to get
involved more actively than they are
involved right now.
And if Pakistan also get gets involved
because Americans use Pakistani
territory for action against Iran, then
the war will be on our doorstep,
Pakistan and Afghanistan are already
fighting a war with each other. So you
see more and more countries could get
could start get getting involved in in
in this war and that becomes a world
war. So this war if it is not contained
could become a world war. We are already
there. Now let's say there's a the World
War II breaks out and the Americans are
in a sustained war which is not ending
and they want to put boats on the ground
or whatever which means they need
soldiers
and let's say they put boats on the
ground it doesn't work work well you
know soldiers die or whatever then they
need more soldiers then they could start
doing uh you know drafting
conscripting people into the army you
know if you are in a state of emergency
you can force people to join the army
that's what's happening been happening
in UK Ukraine they've been forced ing
people, civilians to join the armed
forces. That's what's happening in
Ukraine. So if this happens,
the US could draft people forcibly.
Will they only use the Indian diaspora
as force recruitment? I don't think so.
They will maybe make it mandatory
uh for civilians of a certain age range
to u to get drafted into the military.
that sort of thing situation happened
during the Vietnam war for example and
Muhammad Ali I think he refused and
that's why he went to jail or something
for a while Elvis Presley on the other
hand joined the military for a while so
you've had this sort of situation during
the Vietnam war in the 1960s etc 1960s7s
so if war continues it becomes a major
war it's not ending this sort of thing
could happen in the US uh Canada right
now is not participating in the war. So
that won't happen in Canada. If Canada
also gets involved and they also need
more soldiers, they could draft
civilians into the war effort. But I
don't think they will specifically
single out any any ethnicity or any
community like the Indian diaspora
because that goes against their
constitution and laws. So they will do
it irrespective of what your ethnicity
is. Uh yeah, that is a possibility
long-term possibility if the war
continues.
Argamittal says, "I admire your
knowledge of geopolitics, history and
astronomy. I have read your dark matter
and quantum gravity papers. How did you
pursue astronomy after your after your
studies is ISRO three decades behind the
US?"
Um well, first of all, thank you very
much. Thank you. Thank you. And um thank
you for reading my papers. So, how did I
pursue astronomy after my studies?
Um I have never pursued astronomy. My
pursuit is theoretical physics. Um
it's ast which subset of theoretical
physics astrophysics and cosmology.
Um so how did I pursue that after after
my studies? Yeah after my studies I
started working right but while working
when you have free time you can do your
own research when you are doing
theoretical physics you don't need
equipment you don't need labs you don't
need any of that you need pen paper and
brain and your understanding of the laws
of physics.
Uh so that's how I did it for a while.
Right now I'm not actively doing any
research. It's not been the case for
several years now that I'm not actively
doing research. Um eventually I need to
get back into it. Uh so that's how I did
it. Uh now about ISRO is ISRO three
decades behind the US. Uh look the what
are the American capabilities right now?
They have the world's most powerful
rocket which is a Space X uh uh
Starship.
So what let's let's uh see. So the
Americans have the Starship which is the
most powerful rocket which can which can
launch a tremendous amount of cargo into
Earth orbit and India's most powerful
rocket is the LMV3 or whatever it's it's
a GSV rocket which uh can carry a small
fraction of that payload into orbit.
Uh so that's the gap that we have and uh
technologically I'm sure the Americans
have better technology. They can use AI
and whatnot in in what they're doing.
India can't.
So if ISRO has to bridge the gap and
have a rocket as powerful as the Space X
Starship rocket, how soon can India do
this? So let's let's quickly do a little
bit of analysis.
SpaceX Starship LEO payload
how much?
Okay, so to low earth orbit it can carry
about 150 tons. Massive massive payload.
Okay. Now ISRO
ISRO
GSLV
payload
GSLV can carry six tons. Six tons into
low earth orbit. Starship can carry
150 tons.
So that's a huge huge gap. So let's say
you want to make it 10 times more
powerful which so that it can so that
the GSLV or whatever rocket can carry 60
tons into low earth orbit
which it means that you will need more
power either you will need more powerful
engines or you will need 10 engines
firing together
that can be done. It will take it will
take you like maybe 2 3 years to develop
a rocket that has 10 engines firing
together I suppose
and of course it's multiple stages
yeah we have those solid booster stages
and whatnot so it's it's complex maybe 3
to 5 years India can develop a rocket
that's 10 times more powerful but to
catch up with SP X uh Starship which is
150 tons
uh it will take maybe maybe 10 years. So
I think ISRO may be about 10 years
behind the US if we are being
optimistic. But if we factor in the
Indian bureaucracy and administrators
and all that all that all that stuff
then maybe we are 20 years behind the
US. So overall I think is can catch up
fast if there is funding and if there is
political will and if the bureaucratic
inefficiencies are removed
can be done but looks like there is no
political will in India for this.
Okay. MKV says Vive Ramaswami just
vanished lol. He was dead against the
neocon lobby. Why silent now? Did he did
he get a taste of reality?
I think Vive Kamasami got a taste of
reality.
Okay. Um
he understood I think he will have
understood by now that his ethnicity,
his skin color and his religion are a
major handicap for him in the US in in
in American politics.
And even if he converts to Christianity,
gives up Hinduism, he already pedals
monotheistic form of Hinduism, right?
that we only have one God and I believe
in one God and all that nonsense. Even
if he even if he converts to
Christianity
the first of all there's his skin color
and secondly his name Vivec Ramaswami
that's not an American name
right so he simply doesn't stand a
chance in American politics
you have to be Christian and you to have
an American name
and you have to be a different ethnicity
than Indian you can be brown but you
have to Mexican brown.
So it's not going to work for him and
there's a tremendous amount of
opposition to him. So yeah, he's got I
think he he he's got a big taste of
reality.
Vin says Saudis and Pakistanis are
having a lot of meetings. Will Pakistan
attack Iran as a lot of pressure is
being built up on Munir? Pakistan has a
history of creating problems in Iran. So
I'm not aware of these meetings between
the Pakistanis and the Saudis but maybe
it's happening. Okay. Will Pakistan
attack Iran? Pakistan won't attack Iran
directly unless Iran is very weak. In
that case the Pakistanis will take
advantage like cowards.
Cowards attack those who are down.
Cowards attack those who are weak.
Right? That's that's Pakistan's history.
Um
but right now Pakistan will not attack
Iran. Say anyway Pakistan is is a puppet
of the US. Pakistan is a US vasal. They
will do whatever the Americans tell
them. I'm sure the Americans are
currently using Pakistani uh airspace
for at least surveillance activities
visa v Iran. Let us uh let us see. Give
me a second. Let's see the flight
activity over Pakistan, shall we? Let's
go to flight radar
and see what's happening right now.
Let's see.
Um okay where is okay
so what's going on we have activity over
Pakistan now what kind of aircraft are
we seeing over Pakistan what is this for
example where is it coming from where's
it going Islamaduryad
what is this
fly jina what kind of airline is that
fly jina ethihad so it looks like
civilian aircraft flying over the region
what is this thing here
let's
That's interesting.
That's interesting. Where's it coming
from?
It's coming from the Maldives. Is it?
Looks like that aircraft took off from
the Maldives.
This is Maharu International Airport.
Okay. So, it took off from the Maldives
and it flew over Indian airspace
and now it's it's flying over Pakistani
airspace. I wonder where it's going. We
don't know. Uh do we have any activity
over Iran? Not right now. Is there any
drone flying over here? Sometimes drones
keep the transponders on.
Uh can't say. Okay. So that's the
situation there right now. The the point
is that if the Americans uh tell
Pakistan to do something, the Pakistanis
will do it and the Americans will
definitely be using Pakistani airspace
and maybe Pakistani air bases for
various activities. Uh so eventually
this could this could lead to Iranian
strikes on Pakistan but I'm sure Iran
doesn't want to do it because Pakistan
is a very capable military compared to
Iran at least.
Uh so yeah that that is the situ
situation as this war goes goes on if
the Americans lose their military bases
in West Asia they will possibly have to
start relying on Pakistani air bases in
which case the war will shift towards
Pakistan.
Yeah, we'll see. VSBs says, "Jes,
are you sure this war will last very
long as you said or is it possible it
will end in a short time frame?"
I think it will last long. Now, if it
ends in a short time frame, how can it
possibly how can it potentially end in a
short time frame? It can potentially end
in a short time frame if the Americans
defeat Iran or if Iran defeats the US.
Now, can America defeat Iran? It can't.
That's very clear. Now,
the only way to defeat Iran properly,
fully, is by launching a ground invasion
of Iran. That's suicidal.
So, that won't happen. Iran will keep
fighting. Iran seems to have enough
missiles and drones to last months.
and it will use its missiles and drones
to destroy all the American bases in the
region and destroy Iran Israel's nucle
Israel's military capabilities
right so the war goes on goes on goes on
and America can't withdraw because that
looks like a defeat
and if America says let's have a
ceasefire Iran Iran will say no because
Iran wants to once and for all end the
American military presence in the region
and It's it has the upper hand right
now. So this goes on. I don't see it
ending in a short time frame. Even if
the Americans are quietly trying to do
some backdoor negotiations through
intermediaries for a ceasefire, Iran
will not accept a ceasefire.
So I don't I don't see how this war ends
soon. I hope it ends soon because it's
terrible for everybody including us who
are not fighting it or Yeah. But I don't
see how it ends soon.
I don't see I don't see it ending soon.
Meshov says India with words hinted
Israel support yet Iran allows Indian
tankers to pass through the straight of
Hormos. This perplexes me please
explain.
Yeah, see Iran is not a stupid nation.
Iran has mature diplomats and leaders.
Iran understands the kind of constraints
that India is under.
Iran understands that the Americans are
pressurizing India in various ways and
that Iran understands that America has
been containing India the past few years
and obstructing India's growth and so on
and so forth. Iran also understands that
India need Iran also understands that
India needs the access to the American
economy and so on which is why India is
under various constraints. Iran
understands that Pakistan is a US puppet
that is being used by the Americans to
hurt India and also potentially Iran.
And if Mr. Modi verbally offered what
looks like support to Iran to to Israel
and the US, he has not taken any actions
that will hurt Iran in any way.
Iran India has given refuge to an
Iranian warship in an Indian port
thereby saving one America one Iranian
warship from American torpedoes. So
overall India has not taken any actions
that will hurt Iran. India has taken
actions that actually will be could be
could be portrayed by the Americans as
being anti-America and pro Iran.
Right? And long-term Iran wants a good
relationship with with India and Iran is
now more confident it will survive this
war and actually
win this war and once that happens Iran
wants good relations within India. Iran
wants to keep selling oil to India in
the future resume selling oil to India.
So because of these reasons Iran has
allowed a small number of nations to
have their tankers cross the oil the the
straight of Hormuz and this includes
India. Empty
boxes help me get access to the history
course I brought bought three years ago.
What happened? Is there some problem? U
send me an email with the details of the
problem with your email id and phone
number uh in the email id listed in the
description or in the description of one
of my of any of the videos. Okay.
Somalia Paul says, "Tell me something.
If Iran thinks Israel and the US wanted
to destroy them but Israel tells Iran is
exist existential threat to them who is
actually the one who started this
conflict from the start.
Look, both situations can be true.
Okay, let's let's unpack this entire
issue.
In the 1950s,60s,
etc. '7s also, Iran was ruled by
Muhammad Raza Bahavi
who was an American puppet. His job was
to give full access
of Iranian oil to the west at discounted
prices.
So essentially during Muhammad Raaphaw's
time, Iranian oil was sold to the west
at discounted prices
which was bad for Iran. He made Iran a
complete puppet of the west.
There was a prime minister of of Iran uh
Muhammad Mosade who stopped that who
tried to stop this. He nationalized
Iran's oil industry and stopped giving
preferential treatment to the west and
there was a coup against him. Okay. And
uh Palawi was reinstated as the guy in
power.
So this was the situation before 1979
when Palvi eventually became extremely
unpopular in Iran because he was a
western slave. So eventually there was
an Islamic revolution in Iran
and Mr. Kamei
came to power when the Islamic
revolution succeeded in 1979
and the sha the fake sha was ousted. He
went into exile in the west and Iran the
the new Iranian regime the government
the government of the ayatas the
government of the moolas they declared
the US as enemy number one they declared
the US as shanorg the great Satan
and they also said that Israel has no
right to exist.
Okay.
and they they they
took over the American embassy in Thran
and took a number of diplomats, American
diplomats hostage for more than 400
days. Long story. So Iran became super
hostile to the US
and super hostile to Israel
and in retaliation the Americans induced
Saddam Hussein to launch an invasion of
Iran. There was the Iran Iraq war 1980s
which was a disaster for both nations.
So that's the story. That's how it all
began.
Now
um
now the question you're asking is so so
Israel from Israel's perspective Iran is
a nation that says Israel has no right
to exist. So obviously Israel is right
to be worried about Iran because from
Israel's perspective it has the right to
exist. Israel is a legitimate nation.
Even I would say that of course it is
right. So Iran says it has no right to
exist. Israel says no no no we will
exist. You can't stop us. And then
Israel says that Iran is developing a
nuclear program. Iran does have a
nuclear program. It says that it's for
uh civilian use. It's for power
generation.
But obviously a nuclear program can be
used for other things as well like
creating nuclear weapons. So that's the
issue. Okay. Now, this current conflict,
who started it? Well, there was a war,
12-day war in 2025, last year, which
started with the Israelis launching air
strikes on Iran.
And it ended with American B-52 bombers
destroying Natans and for those two
Iranian nuclear facilities. And then
Trump claimed at the time that Iran's
nuclear program had been destroyed once
and for all.
So last year Trump claimed that Iran's
nuclear program was destroyed, finished
permanently.
Now in 2026, this new war has started.
How did it start? With an Iran with an
Israeli and American attack on Iran
and and and Trump said that we are doing
this war, we have joined this war so
that we destroy Iran's nuclear program.
But did not did Trump not claim last
year that he had ended it?
So that's the thing. So this current
conflict started with an Israeli and
American attack on Iran. They started
the conflict and then they assassinated
Mr. Kamei the supreme leader of Iran.
That's how the conflict started. Overall
that's a story. All right.
Kanglay says no timely action against
cooki illegal immigrants coming from
Myanmar will pay huge to national
security in the next 5 years. What's my
view? I think the situation in Manipur
is a disaster.
I don't understand why we are allowing
foreigners to squat on Indian territory.
How does it advance the Indian national
interest?
History tells us that cookies are
foreigners that they were artificially
artificially settled by the British in
the territory of Manipur to punish the
Manipuris. Who are the Manipuris? The
Mate and the Nagas.
Okay, they are the maid and the nagas
are the indigenous people of Manipur of
this region. The cookies are foreigners.
They are foreigners even to Burma.
And the British themselves never trusted
the cookies. And if you see this the
census records of Manipur, British
census records from 1900 onwards around
that period onwards you will see there
were almost no cookies in Manipur when
the first census was taken and then this
cookie population starts slowly rising
because the British were bringing more
in as a punitive measure. So the British
were bringing foreigners into India into
the kingdom of Manipur right at the
time.
So that is obviously it tells you that
the the cookies don't belong in this
region
and now we have a big cookie population
on the other side of the border inside
Myanmar and the India Myanmar border is
open the Manipur Myanmar border is open
and these the last 10 years or or so if
you see satellite imagur
looks like lacks of cookies have come
into Manipur in the last 10 15 years,
right? And they indulge in all these
terrorist activities. They have a
limitless supply of arms and ammunition.
Previous governments have done this
suspension of operation agreement only
with the cookie terrorists
and now they have taken over more than
half of Manipur and they're terrorizing
the indigenous people of Manipur whether
they are cookie whether they're mates or
nagas. That's an ongoing situation right
now as of today as of yesterday also.
And the government of India doesn't seem
to have control over at least half of
Manipur. The city of Churachpur has been
ethnically cleansed of non-cookies
and there's gunfights happening there.
How come these these people have access
to weapons?
If you go to other parts of India,
people aren't allowed to carry weapons.
People aren't allowed to own weapons.
You to apply for a license which almost
nobody gets.
But cookies openly wander around with
AK-47s and M15s and God knows what kind
of advanced weapons.
India has lost control of at least half
of Manipur.
And imagine how the natives will feel
how imagine how the indigenous people of
this region will feel like the
government of India doesn't give a damn
about them. This is exactly what caused
insurgency in the entire far east of
India from 1947 onwards.
Every state had multiple insurgencies.
Why? Because of the stepmotherly
treatment given to this region by the
government of India in Delhi.
When there is no progress, where when
there is no development, when there is
no food, whether when there are no
opportunities for growth, people become
dissatisfied. They become desperate.
they will say we don't want to be under
your government we want to have our own
country so there were multiple
incidences multiple separatist
insurgencies in every state in India's
far whether it is Assam whether it is
Bizaram whether it is whatever else
Nagaland Manipur
every state had multiple insurgent
outfits outfits separatist outfits and
then the Chinese took advantage of that
the Pakistanis took advantage of that
the Americans took advantage of that so
if India allows this to continue in
Manipur
what do you expect the people the
indigenous people to feel they will feel
that the government of India and the
people of India and the nation of India
doesn't care about us what is that going
to give rise to separatist tendencies
this is what is happening in Manipur
right now
that's my view
sorb says what options does Iran have if
kar island is damaged by the US
Iran has many options
Kirk Island, see what was the thing
about Kirk Island? It had big oil
uh reservoirs, right? If it's been
damaged by the US, the Iranians can
damage oil reservoirs and and depose of
other countries, Gulf countries in the
region,
Iran has all kinds of options.
Iran can go after whatever is left of
the American military bases and destroy
them completely. Iran can bombard Israel
even more heavily.
Is Iran can destroy various oil
refineries and oil
wells in the region. Whether it's in
whichever Gulf country, Iran has all
kinds of options. All kinds of options.
Trump is getting desperate.
There was no military target on Kir
Island.
Let's see K Island, shall we? Um
let us see Cara Island.
Okay, let us go to uh the map and let's
go to the Persian Gulf region.
And where is Kar Island? This is the
island we're talking about. Okay, so as
you can see it is off off the coast of
Iran. Now let's go to the satellite
imagery and let's see what we can u
discern of this island on the on the
face of this island. Do we have any? So
as you can see these are oil reservoirs.
These are oil depots.
This is where oil is stored.
Okay. Lots of oil storage on this
island. I don't see any military
facilities here. This obviously is an
oil tanker that is anchored over here.
Does it have Yeah, it's an oil tanker
clearly. This is not a military ship.
It's not It's not a naval ship. Do we
have anything else here?
Okay, there's a hospital.
There are some residential areas.
There's a stadium there. What is this
here? This also is a residential area.
There's an airport there. Sure. Do we
have any fighter planes here? What is
this? This looks like a non-fighter
plane. Do we have any fighter planes?
Um, I'm not sure I see any any military
aircraft here.
Uh,
at first glance, at cursory glance, it
doesn't look like there's any military
aircraft over here. Uh, what else do we
have? What is NGL? I don't know what NGL
is.
Construction company, power plant. So,
as you can see, it's oil oil storage
facilities, residential areas.
What do we have here?
Yeah. So, I don't see any military
targets on this island. The Americans
say that they've obliterated Trump says
that he has obliterated Ka Island. Well,
that looks like the act of a desperate
person. Yeah. Just to just to plate his
his voters at home.
Ashish Raj thank you very much sirv
Satya says I know treaties exist but
that's just a piece of paper will we see
the militarization of space in our
lifetime is something like rods from god
even possible should India have a space
force see rods from gods is the concept
of taking long rods like telephone poles
and shooting them from space from orbit
onto a target on the planet
theoretically it works.
Yeah. There's nothing in the laws of
physics that prevents that from working.
And the the the the kindinetic energy
such a rod can have is going to be
immense. So it's so you don't need any
explosive charge to cause immense damage
on the target. So theoretically it's
possible but uh but it's never taken off
for whatever reason. I'm not looking
into it but yeah theoretically it works.
Uh but the danger of militarization of
space is when you can start putting
nuclear missiles or whatever into space
uh into
into orbit around the earth.
So that way you don't have to launch a
missile from a place on earth and go on
this ballistic trajectory or whatever.
You can launch it directly from space.
Let's say you have a satellite
which uh will have let's say 10
space missiles which with the nuclear
warheads.
So if you launch that it will need much
less propellant first of all because
it's already in space it will only need
to re-enter and hit the target.
So it will need less propellant which
means the missile can be shorter and
secondly the warning time becomes very
less because if you have if you're
monitoring the the the your adversary
nation and you're wondering if they're
going to launch nuclear missiles then
when a launch happens you have enough
time to react to it. But if a launch
happens from space,
then you have way less time to react to
it. So militarization of space, I think
it's essentially going to be in
inevitable.
As as space programs become more mature
and as technologies improve and advance,
I think it's going to be almost
inevitable that you're going to have
militarization of space. I'm sure the
American military may already have
militarized space and not told us about
it because there are many um you know
classified missions that are launched
you know military satellites and
whatnot. We don't know what's what's on
those satellites. We don't know that um
even even Starlink can be militariz
militarized. I'm sure you can put small
sensors on Starlink satellites
which will not cost which will not be
very heavy and which can monitor the
entire earth in real time. So each
Starlink satellite can possibly can can
potentially be a spy satellite apart
from doing its job of be beaming
internet to the to the surface of the
planet. So I think militarization has
already happened. We may not know about
it. It may be classified. It may be
secret but I'm sure it's already
happening.
Yeah, but see you will be careful not to
reveal it because if your adversaries
come to know that you have put weapons
in space then your adversary may be in a
position position to destroy your
satellites which will be not good for
everybody because it will cause a
tremendous amount of space debris in
orbit around the planet which means
future space launches rocket launches
will become impossible.
So that's the payoff that's a trade-off.
So if you have such capabilities, you
you're going to keep them secret and you
will use them only
as a as something that is uh as as a
last resort thing. So should India have
a space force? I think India should also
have a space force. But first of all, we
need to fix ISRO.
Market whisperer says if not for the
border issue, India and China I feel
could have been natural allies. We have
a lot more in common with China than we
do with the US and ISR. What is ISR?
Thoughts? Okay.
Is Israel Israel
do we
does India have a lot more in common
with China than we have with the US and
Israel? Yes. Civilizationally we are
very similar.
We are both ancient civilizations.
Culturally we have a lot in common.
you meet a Chinese person, it's you
don't feel like I mean there's a lot of
cultural similarities between us and
Chinese people.
So,
so I agree with you that if not for this
border issue, we could have been natural
allies. Even if the border is
demarcated, there's going to be tensions
because two major massive nations with a
shared border, there's always tensions.
The ideal scenario is that Tibet should
never have become part of China. Tibet
should have removed should have remained
a buffer state between India and China.
That way India and China could have been
natural allies. So I completely agree
with you that we have a lot more in
common with China than with the US or
Israel civilizationally and culturally.
The Chinese current Chinese government
is is culturally not very Chinese. Okay.
It's culturally it its cultural
roots are communist, Marxist,
Leninist, Maoist roots. Mao was an enemy
of Chinese civilization. Maong okay. So
that those are the roots. But of course
they now understand the value of culture
and Chinese culture and they use it as
something to that that gives the nation
prestige. So yeah.
Okay. Argl says US, Russia, China have
bomber. What leverage do they get? You
mean strategic bombers, right? So you
can use fighter planes as bombers too.
That's what India does. The Sukoy 30 can
be used as a fighter bomber. Even the
Rafal can be used as a fighter bomber
and so on, right? Uh but the but these
nations US, Russia, China, they have
strategic bombers which are large
aircraft which can carry thousands of
kilograms of ordinance, bombs, cruise
missiles, whatever.
And these large aircraft can fly for
thousands of kilometers and then release
their payloads.
So that allows these nations to to
uh to come very close to their enemy's
border and then launch a massive amount
of uh of ordinance at the targets.
Right? That's that's what happens. Now
should India get a strategic bomber? It
doesn't make sense for India to get one
because
see American strategic bombers they
typically fly over Alaska over the
Pacific Ocean or the Atlantic Ocean or
Europe or territory that is not hostile
to them and then they will launch their
missiles or bombs only when they come
close to the border of any hostile
nation. They are not designed to fly in
hostile territory.
Okay.
Even the Chinese bombers, strategic
bombers,
if they want to attack India, they will
fly over
Shinjang, Tibet etc. which is not
hostile territory and then they will
launch from close to the Indian border.
These strategic bombers are not designed
to fly for long distances over hostile
territory.
So when you have the advantage of
geography, you can have strategic
bombers. Who does India want to attack?
If if if let's say we want to use a
strategic bomber, who do we attack? If
you look at the geography, a strategic
bomber, let's say it has uh
6,000 kilometer range. Okay. So, do we
want to attack some African nation for
example? You you know, makes no sense
for us to do that. Do we want to attack
Southeast Asia? Obviously not. Do we
want to attack Australia? No, obviously
not. Our adversaries are Pakistan and
China. So, yeah, China's industrial base
is far away from India. It's in the
Shenzhen region in the east part of
China
and uh but to have a strategic bomber
attack these territories we will have to
fly over Chinese territory or other
territory which doesn't make any sense.
So for India I think the best thing to
have is to have fighter bombers that can
you know as long as Pakistan exists we
can use fighter bombers to address that
issue and for China we will probably
need ballistic missiles or something if
we ever get get into a war with China.
Does it make sense for India to have
strategic bombers because of
geographical uh considerations?
Dura Panchchal says who winning US Iran
conflict helps India? Iran. If Iran
wins, it's better for India. And I
explained why in great detail multiple
times today. So if Iran wins, it's going
to be strategically more advantageous
for India. If the US wins, it's going to
be a disaster for India because the US
victory means the destruction of Iran
and the end of the current regime in in
Iran.
So that's a disaster for India and
that's not not going to not going to
happen. Vive Singh says many YouTubers
say that the Iran US war is a problem
for China but I think they would like
the war to continue so that
they can gulp Taiwan. Thoughts?
uh I don't know what other YouTubers are
saying but let's try and understand
analyze this uh logically
the war is happening and because of that
China will have constraints will will
face problems when when it comes to
their oil supply which means that they
will have to import more Russian oil
they will already have placed big orders
and the oil has to come all the way from
the North Atlantic transition transit
through the Mediterranean then through
Su then through the Red Sea then through
the baland strait then through the
Indian Ocean and then reach China maybe
it takes like 354 days but they they can
get sufficient oil from Russia. So from
an oil perspective it's a problem
temporarily for the next couple of
months but then it'll be fine for China.
Now the deal the the thing about this
war that America is fighting against
Iran is that it is consuming a lot of
American
munitions and missiles.
The American interceptor missiles have
all but
become depleted in West Asia. That's why
America is moving its THAD systems from
South Korea into the West Asia theat
which is leaving South Korea more more
vulnerable. In the first 3 days of the
war, the Americans used up about 20% of
their global Tomahawk missile inventory.
So the longer this war continues, the
more the American stocks of various
kinds of weapons will get depleted,
right? And if the Americans start
running short of arms, ammunition, and
all that, well, isn't that good for
China and Russia? Of course it is.
And the longer the war continues, the
more the Chinese and the Russians can
learn the lessons of the war that what
is working for Iran that it's able to
dominate this war. If not dominate,
survive this war and
you know prevent the Americans from
achieving any of their objectives.
From that perspective, Iran is is
winning. So, so the lesson of the war is
that you need thousands of ballistic
missiles and hundreds of thousands of
drones. The Chinese have quietly been
stockpiling, I'm sure, lots of drones
and missiles too. And now we understand,
we can clearly see the American
vulnerabilities, the American uh
military strategies, how they can be
defeated. And the the same lessons can
be used to defeat the Americans in the
eastern theater in Taiwan, in South
Korea, in Japan possibly. Right? So the
longer this war goes on, the better it
is for China. I don't think it's a
problem for China.
Authan
owe all my geopolitical knowledge to
you. Thank you very much, sir. Thank you
very much.
Java bro says did we have razors
or barbers at the times of Siam I don't
know
we don't even know what was the time of
Shiridam we don't have a date we don't
have an appro approximate date we have
various propos proposed dates but we
don't know which one is correct
um
but I'm sure people would have shaved in
some way so I don't know for sure we
don't know for sure because we don't
know what in what time period this
happened so can't have a answer right
now.
Ad Astra says, "Reliance setting up a
refinery in Texas. Worrying. Why is it
worry? It's okay. It's okay."
Um, it doesn't harm India's interests in
any way. It does not, right?
It's fine.
Mary Kane says, "Nuclear. No computer
can ru can run all chess moves. No
gazillions of supercomputers could run
chuck chakra view aerial combinations.
Question, would powering supercomputers
with micro reactors
versus small modular reactors make more
sense?
Uh, a supercomputer obviously is a large
computer which which needs a large
amount of power, reliable power.
Um,
and you can connect a supercomputer to
the to the grid in the city and it'll
run just fine. But if you want a
supercomputer to have its own dedicated
power supply to ensure that there is no
issue if the city's grid goes down for
even momentarily,
then it makes sense to to connect a
supercomput to its own power power
source like a micro reactor or a small
modular reactor.
Um it's it's definitely a good idea as a
backup option. So you connect the
supercomputer to the city's grid, but
you keep a micro reactor, let's say, as
a backup. So in case there's an issue,
your circuit automatically and instantly
switches to the micro reactor. Yes, that
that makes sense. Or you can even have
it powered exclusively by the micro
reactor. in which case you would want to
have one another micro reactor as a
backup because you always want to have a
backup when it comes to uh critical
computing.
Um so no computer can run all chess
moves. Yeah, no computer can run all
chess moves. Uh no gazillions of
supercomputers could run chakra view
aerial combinations. I suppose not
because the combinations are essentially
endless.
Yeah. So I would say uh
it makes sense to power supercomputers
with micro reactors. Yeah. Depending on
the context depending Yeah. Whether it
is a military supercomputer or a
supercomputer used for weather modeling
or whatever. If it's a supercomputer
used for weather modeling then in in
that case it's not that critical. If
it's a military supercomput yes you need
to have redundancies built into the
power supply.
Fast snail says is the US facing a
similar situation? is the Vietnam War.
Not quite yet. Not yet. In the Vietnam
War, the Americans put boots on the
ground. They tried to invade Vietnam.
They brought in lots and lots of
soldiers.
They drafted people against their wishes
into the military.
That caused lots of political problems
in the US. So, that's not the situation
that you have right now. Right now, the
Americans are trying to pound Iran into
submission. It's not working. They are
taking big damage. uh the Americans have
not put a single boot on the ground. So
right now it's not a similar situation
as the Vietnam war. No. But if this war
drags on and Trump becomes desperate for
a win and if he has American soldiers
put their boots on the ground and try
and and attempt an invasion, a ground
invasion of Iran, then it starts
becoming possibly potentially similar to
the Vietnam war. Right now it is not the
case. But uh what are the similarities?
The similarities is that in Vietnam the
Americans failed to achieve their
objectives and in Iran right now they're
failing to achieve their objectives
right now. So that is this little bit of
similarity but all over overall it's not
similar.
Godliness says previously I mentioned
how many of our exservicemen are
egoistic and have no knowledge of
strategic communication. today. Let me
also proclaim when it comes to war
reporting, our media is disastrous.
Um, okay. I'm not sure about our uh
ex-servicemen. Okay, ex-servicemen and
okay, when it comes to war reporting,
our media is disastrous. Our media is
terrible. Our media is absolutely
terrible. When it comes to war
reporting, the biases are obvious, open,
blatant. When it comes to Indian media,
the Indian media's reporting of the
Ukraine war. It's it's
pathetic reporting. Completely
one-sided. Just just regurgitating
regurgitating western talking points. A
couple of media channels may have sent
Indian reporters on the ground over
there, but only on Ukrainian territory.
If you want to have balanced coverage,
send two reporters on Ukrainian
territory and send two two reporters on
Russian territory and let's have
coverage from both sides. No, it's only
going to be one-sided. So the Indian
media is trash,
very low quality media and right now
when it comes to the reporting of the
Iran war, the less said than the lesser
the better about the Indian media.
Rebel Sports says, "What do you think
will be the impact of the war on East
and Southeast Southeast Asia excluding
India? We're talking about Indonesia,
Malaysia, Singapore, Thailand, Sri
Lanka, etc. Well, for these nations, the
main issue is going to be availability
of uh energy, oil and gas, right?
Uh that's going to be impacted.
See, most of these nations, they import
their oil from from the Hormos region,
right? From the straight of Hormos and
that's going to be impacted. Um that's
the immediate impact of of the war on
these nations. and they will also have
to purchase oil from Russia or the
United States or whatever. So they're
going to have to make arrangements,
alternative arrangements. Apart from
that, these nations are not involved in
the war. So they're not taking sides in
the war. Uh so and and so I don't see
any any other impact of the war on these
nations. Sri Lanka has been dragged into
into the into the war in in a small way.
uh they have given refuge to one Iranian
warship in the port of Trinko Mali and
we know another Iranian warship was
destroyed by an American submarine very
close to Sri Lankan territorial waters
so Sri Lanka has been impacted in that
manner apart from that nothing much
joy says can war force India into true
self-reliance
it can
only if we have the right leadership who
takes the hard decisions
Otherwise no war will succeed in forcing
you into self-reliance
right so this is this war can be seen by
India as an opportunity
become completely self-reliant in terms
of our defense equipment and so on
build a defense industry urgently on a
war footing make everything indigenous
start using cavary engines whether they
are good or had in some aircraft
and see how it performs. That's how the
west started.
It's it's you know after 194 after 1945
that's what the west did. The initial
jet engines were terrible but they
started using them and kept improving
them over time. India needs to do that.
India needs to revamp its space program
completely.
India needs to become a massive producer
of drones and missiles.
So India needs to discover oil in its
territory. I'm sure there's oil
tremendous amount of reserves of oil
sitting around but we have never
bothered. Right now the government of
India is trying to explore beginning the
process of exploring.
Right now the government of India is
beginning the process of exploring uh
for oil in the Andaman region. My
question is why did this not start in
2014?
Why was this process not started in
2014? Why is it being started right now?
Was the government of India sleeping for
a decade? Anyway, do it now. I'm sure
there's a lot of oil there. Gas also
discover it. So the war can face India
in can force India into true
self-reliance only if India the
government if the Indian leadership does
the difficult things the hard things the
painful things and reforms the country
otherwise nothing will happen.
Richest Pakistani
richest Pakistani great name. Good
evening. Uh your critical thinking
insights have deeply shaped my mindset
as an AI engineer. Well I'm glad to hear
that sir. My recent internship at IIT
Madras AI for Bharat reinforced my pride
in contributing to India and thank you
for your impactful guidance. You are
very welcome sir. It's so nice to see
your message
and I'm glad that you have recently
interned at IIT Madras AI for BAT and
please continue. I'm glad that you feel
pride in contributing to India to bhat
and please continue that sir. Absolutely
sir ma'am I think yeah I don't know yeah
so you are very welcome I'm I'm very
pleased to hear this and I wish you
nothing but continuing success all the
best sir do well do very well
snail
fast snail says does the US benefit from
hormones blockade more exports shortterm
it's going to be a disaster for the
world long-term the US will benefit if
the hormones rate of hormones is
blockaded for a long time um and if
nobody
is able to receive oil coming through
hormones, then the Americans can benefit
because then the Americans can start
become can start exporting oil their oil
to other countries
and other things as well. But if Iran
selectively allow some nations to
purchase to to to acquire to have oil
pass through the straight of Hormuz,
then the US doesn't benefit. Then the US
loses out,
right?
And there if this leads eventually to
the to the trade of oil in currencies
that are non US dollar currencies that's
again disastrous for the US.
So a blockade of hormones can benefit
the US long run only if it is a complete
blockade and no oil or no other stuff is
flowing through hormos. But if things
are flowing through Hormuzu's own
Iranian terms to nations that Iran
designates as friends, then the US
doesn't benefit at all. It's a disaster
for the US. Okay, there we have it.
Jivarus, is India sovereign enough to
fight despite sanctions?
India can fight with despite sanctions.
I think India still has enough
sovereignty to fight if required despite
sanctions. In case hypothetically
sanctions are placed on India, I think
that may actually be beneficial for
India. If sanctions are put on India,
there'll be short-term pain but
long-term India will become more
atmanable and self-reliant
and maybe more sovereign.
Yeah.
Rahun Rajar says, "Are you sure nuclear
won't stop Iran? Sar was 60 years ago.
There must be 10 times or 100 times more
powerful of the US." No.
There's a limit to the explosive power
of a nuclear weapon.
That sar bomba was a massive massive
thing 50 kilotons.
They wanted a 100 kiloton explosion but
technological constraints for them to
limit it to 50 kilotons. The American
nuclear weapons aren't massive gigaton
nuclear weapons, right? They have the W
something and and so on standard nuclear
warheads.
And it's not about vaporizing a country
or something. It's nuclear weapons are
not supposed to vaporize a country
country entirely. They're supposed to
have a achieve help you achieve
strategic objectives.
Mostly most nuclear weapons are going to
be tactical warheads. A certain number
are going to be strategic warheads maybe
in in with an explosive output of
several megatons. Maybe 1 megaton, maybe
10 megatons. I don't think the Americans
have any Tar Bomba like weapon right
now. And even if they use it, what are
they going to achieve? They're going to
horrify the world and the world will
stop working with the US.
So if the Americans want to defeat Iran,
a 100 megaton weapon will not defeat
Iran.
It'll make Iran even more resilient. And
if you if you use 10 of those,
that's going to be the war crime to end
all war crimes.
So you see nuclear. So
if the Americans want to defeat the Iran
regime, they're going to have to use
tactical weapons,
kiloton weapons, maybe 20 kilotons,
Hiroshima, Nagasaki range, you know,
caliber weapons like maybe 20 kilotons,
maybe 30, 50 kilotons, that sort of
thing.
But even if they use 20, 30 of these,
it's not going to be able to defeat a
nation of the size of Iran.
So
I am 100% sure even nuclear weapons
won't stop Iran.
Minimalist Maverick says what reforms
will US make at home to win wars the
next time?
What reforms will the US make at home? I
I don't know. They will have to figure
it out. Their nuclear their military
doctrine is super deficient. See, I'll
tell you why the US is losing this war.
or or not winning this war. The US
approach to war fighting is bulldozer.
It's it's the bulldozer method. What
they do is they carpet bomb nations.
They have a brute force approach
and that brute force approach they have
tried on and it's failed. So in when
that doesn't work, they have no idea
what to do next. Their military approach
isn't nuanced and sophisticated. It's a
brute force approach. That's what they
used in Iraq. That's what they used in
Libya. They simply flatten nations.
But that's not working with Iran.
So now that that's not working, they
have no idea what to do what to do next.
So they don't have a plan B. Trump is
still trying the brute force force
approach, right? Kir Island. That was a
brute force approach that he tried. Uh
where is it? Give me a second. Kir
Island. Where is his tweet? Give me a
second.
I'll put the tweet out again.
Where is that? Where is that? Where is
that? Um,
let me put this on the screen, shall I?
So,
the US is still trying to use the brute
force approach. This is an example of
that.
Uh Trump tweeted this today early
morning about India's time. Moments ago
at my direction, the US Central Command
executed one of the most powerful
bombing raids in the history of the
Middle East and totally obliterated any
every military target in Iran's crown
jewel Ka Island.
He is still trying the brute force
approach even though it is failing.
You see, this is visible evidence of the
US having no plan B. They only know one
way of fighting a war. Brute force. When
when that doesn't work, they have no
idea what to do after that. So, they're
going to have to find I don't know,
rethink everything, I suppose. Anonymous
scientist, good to see you. Mosswan
is now saying that Ukraine will be
attacked because it's helping Israel in
the US. How can it affect the progress
of this Iran USIsrael war? Okay, I have
not seen this uh this uh development but
I'm sure it's happening.
So Iran says that Ukraine will be
attacked because it's helping Israel and
the US. I'm sure see Ukraine is an
American vasal right now. UK Zalinski is
completely dependent on the US and
Europe and Israel to maybe because
Israel is in the same it's essentially
the same as the US. So Zalinsky will do
whatever the Americans ask him to do.
So I am sure see is Ukraine has a lot of
in the last 3 four years they have
gained a lot of experience in using
drones right so they will share that
experience and the tech that knowhow
maybe the technology with the Americans
and the Israelis
and I'm sure the Iranians are keeping
are keeping an eye on this development.
So, if the Iranians attack Isra attack
Ukraine, is it even feasible? First of
all, let's take a look at the map. Yeah.
Is it feasible for Iran to attack
Israel?
Give me a second. Let's put the map on
the screen.
So, here is the map. Now, how far is
Ukraine from Iran? Let's see. How far is
Ukraine from Thran?
Uh how far is Odisa from Dhran? It's
about 2,000 km. It's well within the
range of Iranian missiles.
Yeah, it's well within the range of
Iranian missiles, Ukraine. So if Iran is
making this threat, I'm sure they have
the capability to carry out this threat.
So let's say this happens and uh Iran
attacks Israel,
whatever I saying, Iran attacks Ukraine.
How can this affect the progress of the
Iran of this war? Well, I'll tell you
how it affects the progress of the war.
It draws more countries into the war. It
takes you one step closer to a World War
II scenario, right? So, if Iran is now
fighting Isra Ukraine as well,
maybe they they take out Zalinski.
Maybe they take out Zalinski. The
Americans took out Kamei.
Maybe the Iranians go after Zillinsky.
Who knows? So it could take the war in
all kinds of unexpected directions
and that
increases the possibility of this
becoming World War II. Yeah.
And it's going to be a setback for the
US if the Iranians start targeting
Ukraine. Now Aurora says, "Big fan from
the from the US." Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. I want to know
where is Netanyahu and where do
presidents where are presidents kept
during war? Is it true he died? It's an
X everywhere. So, I don't know what's
happened to Netanyahu. Give me a second.
Um,
yeah, that's a question about what has
happened to this guy. Um, is he alive?
Is he not? Let's let me put out this
tweet again on screen. Last time I saw
it was this.
Um,
give me a second. Let me share this. So
yesterday about 24 hours ago the the
official Twitter account of the prime
minister of Israel tweeted this official
statement from Prime Minister's office
rumors circulating on social media about
Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's
status are unconfirmed.
So even uncon even
the prime minister's office says it's
unconfirmed because which means that
they are not sure about what's happened.
Secondly, they say that efforts are
underway to establish contact which is
an admission that they have no contact
with with Netanyahu.
So there are two two unwitting
admissions here. First that Netanyahu's
status is unconfirmed even by the
government of Israel and secondly the
government of Israel is trying to
establish contact with Netanyahu which
means that they have no contact with
him. This was 24 hours ago, slightly
more than 24 hours ago, and then they
deleted the tweet,
which means they realized that they said
too much.
So, I don't know if he's dead or not,
but that tweet is very well, it is very
concerning if you are a citizen of
Israel or if you are in the west. If you
are supporting Israel in the US, it's
very concerning for you. So, I don't
know what is the situation with Benjamin
Netanyahu. Let me try and see more. Is
is it trending? What is trending? Let's
see what's trending on Twitter right now
about Mr. Netanyahu. Let's see.
Uh what is trending?
Uh let's see what is the latest. Let's
see what's the latest.
Um Netanyahu Benjamin Netanyahu.
This looks like an This is possibly an
AI image.
It's possible this could be an AI image.
So I can't say Grock keeps saying that
Nathaniel is alive based on what
happened on March 12. Well, hey, this is
March 14th.
So Grock is going to keep saying that
Netanyahu is alive.
Uh but lots of people are saying he's
dead. So looks like we don't know what
the situation is right now. It's all
speculation on Twitter. Okay. Uh so I
don't know where he is. I don't know
what his status is but uh yeah looks
like
looks like u you know something may have
happened to him but I can't say for
sure. Now, where are presidents kept
during wartime? If there is the
possibility of strikes where the
president is, they are usually kept in
very secure bunkers, typically
underground in secure locations. That's
where a president is typically kept
because the president is the most
valuable person in the government and
the decision maker. And there's
typically a chain of command. Let's say
that president is taken out. Then who
takes over immediately? That is all
wellestablished.
I mean any any any serious country it's
like that.
All right.
Surabi says, "Is US aiming for Raf
Peters blood borers fracturing the Gulf
while the Americas become the main oil
suppliers? What would India gain or
lose?" Okay, let's see what is this. Ra
Peters blood borders. This was a
speculative map put out a long time ago
where the entire region's maps borders
are reconfigured. Okay.
Ro Ralph
Peters
blood borders. So based on ethnic uh
ethnic groups he had put out this this
thing you know. So is the US aiming for
this? Maybe they were aiming for it but
you can aim for the moon and the stars
but you should have the capability to to
make it happen.
Excuse me. The US clearly is not going
to be able to do this right now because
they are not winning this war against
Iran.
uh how would what would India gain or
lose? Well, it depends on whether it
happens or not. If Pakistan is broken
up, it'll be good for India, right? So,
if if this reconfiguration also
reconfigures Pakistan's borders and if
Pakistan is also broken up and if that
contributes to the decline of terrorism
coming out of Pakistan, that would be a
substantial benefit that India would
gain in that case. But if it does not
stop the terrorism coming out of
Pakistan, it's bad for India. If Iran
gets bulcanized hypothetically
then again it could not be good possibly
be bad for India depending on who comes
to power in various parts of Iran and
that sort of thing. So it is all
speculation. It's all ifs and buts and
hypotheticals and uh
which way it goes will determine whether
India gains or lose.
Black Panther says if Iran falls China
only left out on American radar with the
will the situation force them to settle
the border dispute with India. If so, we
have accept or not. Look, I'll tell you
what. If Iran falls, China is not next
for the Americans.
If Iran falls, India is next.
Okay? Because India is currently
resisting American attempts to vasalize
us.
India is currently resisting
America. America wants India as a vasal
state. India is currently not a vasal
state.
India may have accepted certain ownorous
conditions for the trade deal or
whatever or whatever whatever
India may have given some concessions to
the US but India has not agreed to terms
that will make us aal so that has not
happened if Iran falls the Americans
will come after India next
not China
it's a stepby-step process
first Venezuela
then Iran then India
then they'll deal with China and Russia.
Okay? If Iran falls and China probably
will want to end the border dispute with
India
but Iran is not falling
and it doesn't mean that if Iran falls
it's good for India. No, it's actually
going to be much worse for India if Iran
falls.
Okay. Okay. Pratik Kumar Roy says, "What
will happen if we mistakenly fire
if we mistakenly fire 1,000
nuclear missiles into the US or China?
We don't have 1,000 nuclear missiles.
If we do it, we will start a world war.
We will start a nuclear exchange which
will destroy the world. If let's say
India has 1,000 nuclear warheads and
1,000 missiles to carry them and we if
we if you fire that into the US, the US
will fire 2,000 back at India, it'll
destroy India.
If you fire that at China, it'll destroy
China. And China probably does not have
1,000 nuclear missiles. So, but but the
Chinese will fire back 400 or 500
missiles in India. So, there is
stupidity. That's madness. Nobody does
that.
Black Panther says nowadays all India
parties are busy with an announcement of
cash reward manifesto for election with
okay we don't know how to stop this
nonsense giving free money. I don't know
what the solution is. The solution is an
end of the system.
The current system we should either have
a presidential system or a full
dictatorship.
Now a lot of you will say dictator a
dictatorship is horrible. So okay let's
have a presidential system
in a presidential system you don't have
this s sort of nonsense. So the Indian
system is the biggest problem that India
has. This Westminster
parliamentary democracy that we have
that's the biggest problem that India
has right now. Right?
So if we transition to a to a
presidential system, it'll be great for
us. It'll be good first step for us for
solving many of the problems that we are
saddled with.
Fast snails as does history prove the US
doesn't do well in long wars.
Um, how many long wars have the
Americans fought?
When did the Americans enter the the
Second World War? The First World War,
the Americans were not in that
Pearl Harbor attack date.
Okay. The Americans entered the war at
the end of 1941.
So they were in World War II, let's say
from 1942 to 1945. So that's about 2 and
a half years and by the time it was
done, right? It was not very long from
their perspective.
Uh how long did the Vietnam war last?
Let's see. How long did the Vietnam War
last?
19 years, etc. That was a disaster for
the US. So if you take those two data
points, World War II versus Vietnam War,
clearly the longer war was a disaster
for the US. Um, and the Americans have
fought all kinds of other wars also.
But let's talk about the 20th century,
not not wars before that. So yeah, it
looks like the Americans don't do well
in long wars.
Right now, the situation
is a short thus far, it's been a short
war, but the Americans are already doing
poorly in this one. So if you take the
data point of the Vietnam war, yes, they
did not do well in that war. Were they
part where did they fight other wars in
the 20th century
and no major wars I can think of apart
from the Vietnam war.
Yeah. So yeah, 20th century Vnumber it
was a disaster for them but I don't have
a pattern that's re recurring. So we'll
see about Iran. Godliness says US may
leave but Israel will keep on going.
Then what? Then the war goes on.
But if the Americans end the war from
their perspective, Israel keeps
fighting,
then the Americans will have to keep
resupplying Israel
and then it may keep on going for a
while until it says, "Okay, now I need
to do the Samsung thing." Um, but even
that will not defeat Iran. So yeah,
Gigad says, Giga Dad says playing the
devil's advocate. Why not sacrifice
sovereignty to the west in exchange for
prosperity? In exchange for prosperity
like South Korea, Japan, they are
surrounded by enemies by enemies like
us, US.
See, yeah, it's it's a very tempting
thing, right? sacrifice sovereignty. Our
leaders are third rate leaders. They are
worthless leaders. Let us become
American puppets. The Americans will
decide who rules India, which leader
seems to be in power and then we get
prosperity. But you see Pakistan has
sacrificed it sovereignty for decades.
Did they become prosperous like South
South Korea or Japan? No. Pakistan is a
lowquality population with a
disastrously pathetic education system.
So the Pakistanis despite being
sovereign are a basket case. They are a
failed state.
But let's say India becomes prosperous
like South Korea or Japan.
But look at the condition of South Korea
and Japan. In South Korea,
the native culture has been destroyed by
the Americans. Most Kore South Koreans
are either atheists or Christians. Very
little Buddhism left. Secondly, the
South Koreans are being worked to death.
They are not having babies anymore. What
is South Korea's TFR? Let's see.
South Korea TFR
graph.
Look at this. This is what the Americans
have done to Korea. South Korea.
1965 the TFR starts dropping, dropping,
dropping, dropping, dropping, dropping,
dropping. In 1990 onwards it it rises a
little bit and then starts dropping
again. It's an absolute disaster. Let's
see Japan TFR graph
Japan
total fertility rate. Look at what's
been done to Japan as well. Uh do we
have Statista?
So here also it's a disaster. It's 1.3
right now. So this is what ends up
happening to you if you are a vasal and
Japan's economy was doing so good and
then the Americans destroyed it. So they
will use you as long see not they I'm
not talking about the Americans I'm
talking about anybody any overlord will
use you as long as you're useful and
then they will destroy you. That's what
happens long term is a vasal shortterm
for a decade or two for even five
decades you may have prosperity but at
some point in time they will sacrifice
you. So, not a good idea.
Droop says, "21-year-old no degree run
AI agency. US clients made $6,000 tips."
Uh, first of all, congratulations. You
have an AI agency. No degree doesn't
matter. Who cares? As long as you have
the, you know, the fire in you and the
desire to do well. So, you are running
an AI agency. You have American clients.
You made $6,000. What's my tips?
My tips,
well, I'll say you clearly have done
well. You have achieved a certain amount
of success. My tip is that whatever
gave you the success that you earned
$6,000, I don't know what period of time
you earned it in, but you clearly made
money. Whatever worked for you, you need
to systematize that, create systems out
of that so that you can
keep that running.
and keep earning in that manner
and then you have to build upon that and
improve upon that. So you you need to
document for yourself
what is it that worked for you? Which
business which business processes have
you created or what's the workflow
you've created that has worked for you?
You need to turn that into a repeatable
process.
Okay? And if you're running an AI
agency, obviously you should incorporate
AI into all of this and maybe have AI
run the processes as much as possible,
get more clients and and make more
money.
So, good job. Great. I'm I'm glad to
hear that you've succeeded in earning a
certain amount of money and keep earning
more, right? Um and have a target for
yourself by the end of let's say this
year. How much do you want to be earning
per month? then
and then you need to uh
reverse engineer the how you going to
achieve that much.
So that's what I would say create
systems, create processes, automate as
much as possible. Whatever has worked,
improve upon that. Whatever lessons
you've learned from whatever did not
work well, make sure that you you
incorporate incorporate that wisdom into
your processes and go for it. All the
best.
S Morgan says, "Iran allows our ships.
Maybe it's linked to the guests at our
ports.
The US seemed very interested in them.
Maybe some important someone important
on them."
Um, guests at our ports. So we have what
guests are you talking about? At our
ports, multiple ports. We have one
Iranian warship which is docked at Kochi
and there's more than 100 sailors maybe
close to 200 sailors who are who were
housed by India in Indian naval
headquarters.
That's in one port. I don't know about
multiple ports. So we have Iranian
guests at in one location and they are
not our hostages. we're not going to
mistreat them in any way whatsoever. So
it's not like we are saying to Iran that
you know we have your guys and that's
why you you need to behave. It's not
like that.
Um do we have any other guests at our
ports? I'm not aware about that. I'm not
aware of that. The US seemed very
interested in them. I'm I don't know
what what you are referring to actually.
Um
so yeah, why is Iran allowing Indian
ships? Because Iran wants to have
maintain good relations with India. Iran
thinks it's going to win this war. It's
going to survive and long-term it wants
to continue to have to have a good
positive mutually beneficial
relationship with India. Iran knows that
India has not taken any actions that
that harm Iranian interests and that's
why Iran is allowing our ships. That's
how I see it. Pratip Kumar Royce says
US, Russia, China, India, Israel, Iran,
Korea, Saudi, Pakistan, UK, Brazil,
Australia. Compare all the above with DC
Marvel superheroes, heroes or villains.
I don't watch DC Marvel stuff. The last
movie I watched was Multiverse of
Misery. It was so boring. I was asleep
for half the movie. I don't watch this
stuff. I don't know which villains to
compare them with. I'm so sorry. I don't
know. Thanos. Thanos. I know one villain
called Thanos. I know Thor.
Who is Thor in this? I don't know who's
Thanos in this. Perhaps the US is
Thanos. Others, I have no idea.
I have no idea. Let's see.
Godliness says, "Hypothetically, can
this war frustrate the whole world
enough for the best eagle to repeat 1945
Japan and justify it?" a quick solution
for peace, liberty, and justice.
I think Trump is close to being
frustrated enough for him to consider
that option, the nuclear option. The
problem is even if he uses nukes, it
won't defeat Iran. And there won't be
peace, liberty, justice, or any of the
BS that they pedal.
Yeah,
I don't see that happening. I don't see
that succeeding. Even if they use nukes,
Iran will keep fighting.
See, Iran is a mountainous territory.
Even a nuclear explosion in one place
will the blast will be contained. And if
there is nuclear fallout, which which
there will be, it will go across not
just Iran but the other other countries
including Israel
because wind takes nuclear you know
radiation everywhere.
Chernobyl taught us that.
Um, so even if they use nukes, it won't
work. Iran will keep fighting and they
won't be defeated. Black Panther says,
"What if Japan turned the table against
US?" Now, if that is the case, why
doesn't India turn the tables against
Pakistan and China now?
It doesn't work like that. How will
Japan turn the tables? How, not what if,
how will they do it? They are under
permanent occupation. They've got tens
of thousands of American soldiers on the
territory. How will they turn the
tables? Not possible.
Aurora says, "What is the way for Iran
to win? Can they succeed?" The way for
Iran to win
is to survive.
The way for Iran to win is to not be
defeated.
The way for Iran to win is to frustrate
the Americans so badly that they
consider sending ground troops which
will be suicidal. The way for Iran to
win is to simply outlast the enemy.
The Americans are running short of arms,
ammunition, munitions, missiles,
interceptors. They're running short of
everything.
Just keep the war going longer and
longer. Weaponize time. That is the way
for Iran to win. And that's what they're
doing. And keep the straight of Hormos
closed and allow certain selected
nations to to for their ships to transit
the Straight of Hormos. Everybody else
is blocked. Iran is doing exactly what
it takes to win. Can they succeed? They
are succeeding.
Ammon Tari says, "Do you think India
should create its own proxies like Iran
to tackle threats emanate emerging from
its enemy states?" Sure.
Sure.
Absolutely.
India should do it. The games that
others play, India should also play
those games.
Jay Thiari says, "If the US struggles to
protect its bases abroad, should India
assert stronger strategic autonomy and
push back against US pressure?" Yes.
Yes. Yes, we should.
The US is on its way to losing its
military presence
in West Asia and thereby its ability to
project power in the region. If that
happens, India should assert itself more
strongly because that gives India more
leverage. Now the US seeks to contain
India but they are being contained out
of West Asia. That obviously is is going
to be beneficial for India because the
US is behaving like behaving like a
hostile nation right now the past few
years. So yes, India should assert
stronger strategic autonomy and push
back against US pressure. Yes.
Bman Gopinat says is Iran dragging the
war and finish enemy by targeting BB?
The Iran is Iran wants this war to
continue. They want to completely fully
totally annihilate and end the American
military presence in the region. Um
that's what they want to do and that's
why even if they are offered a ceasefire
right now they will not agree. They will
not accept the ceasefire targeting BB.
We don't know about that. They are
targeting Israel for sure. They're doing
a pretty successful job of that right
now. It looks like uh the status of BB
Netanyahu we don't know right now. We'll
have to see. Aman Kumar Dhankar says no
US bases in West Asia may leave dent on
petro dollar. It's going to be very
bad for the petro dollar. If the
Americans lose their ability to project
power in the region the petro dollar is
over. It's over.
Geo warrior says if the deep state
exists did it make a mistake in letting
the US enter the war or do they have an
ulterior motive here? What do you think?
So the question is what is the deep
state?
The deep state
it's the unelected
establishment that rules the US. That's
the deep state. But maybe there's a
small number of people who control that.
Who are those people?
Now it looks like it doesn't look like
it's very clear the Israel dragged the
US into this war, right? And Trump was
given apparently bad advice that they
will war win the war in two days or
whatever.
So if Israel dragged the US into the
war, it means that the Israelis have
that much control over the US. So maybe
the deep state is Israeli perhaps.
Perhaps.
So did it make a mistake in letting the
US enter the war? No. They wanted the US
to get involved in the war. That is the
motive. So the ulterior motive seems to
be to serve Israeli interests.
That could be the ultimate motive. I
think it's pretty open now.
Black Panther says, "Will India will
India
will India to arm Afghanistan destroy
Pakistan and military infrastructure?"
India is not arming Afghanistan. The
Pakistanis are claiming that India is
involved in the war between Pakistan and
Afghanistan. But India is not arming
Afghanistan. India is investing in
Afghanistan. We've done we've been doing
it for decades and our investments are
purely non-military in nature. We have
invested how how have we invested by by
building dams by building libraries by
building the parliament house by
investing in in in agricultural projects
and so on. That's how India has
invested. We have not weaponized
Afghanistan any any way whatsoever.
Abai Singh says US deploying 2500
marines to Iran just optics. Let's find
out. Is it true?
US Marines Iran.
Let's see. US sending 2500 2500 Marines
to Middle East. To the Middle East. More
US Marines and warships being moved to
Middle East. It's being deployed to the
Middle East, not to Iran.
Okay.
It's not being these Marines are not
being deployed to Iran. They are being
being deployed to the Middle East. Is it
just optics? I don't think it's optics.
Maybe they plan to use those Marines for
something.
Is it optics? I think it's desperation.
Alarm bells have are going off right now
in the US that we are losing this war.
It is going very badly for us.
The war is going very badly for the US
despite what Trump is claiming on
Twitter and on Truth Social or whatever
social. Yeah. So alarm bells are going
off and that's why they they're
deploying Marines and whatnot to to West
Asia.
My movies says best leader in the
history of the of India and the world.
The two great leaders I can think of are
Sri Ram and Shri Krishna.
Aman Kumar Dankar Dhankar says apart
from economy and oil what binds
China retaliate hard
apart from economy and oil
what binds China
what's the question what binds China
retaliate hard
I am not sure what you're asking let me
think
so China apart from economy and oil
what? No, I I don't I don't I don't get
the question. Sorry.
Uh Pratam Si says, "How to do pranayam?
You said you will teach us."
I can't teach you on a live stream.
Maybe I'll have to make a video for
that. Pranayam is very simple, right?
There are millions of videos out there
about pranayam. How to do pranayam. When
it comes to the special pranayam,
walking pranayam, well, that is special.
I don't think there's any video about
that. Maybe I'll make something. I can't
teach you right now about that. Yeah.
But yeah, Abai Singh says a few army and
defense experts from India have claimed
that the B-52 bombing Iranian nuclear
sites was a rehearsed hoax. The US and
Iran were both were in on it. I don't
know. Let them claim whatever. I have no
idea. How do they know?
How do they know? Is that a just a
theory or have has somebody told them
this? If someone told them were the
Americans, were the Iranians, were they
both? Do they have such deep contacts
everywhere? These fantastic experts I
have no idea. So I'll not comment about
that.
Sarram says is a strong adharmic
India greater than a weak dharmic India
for me a yes.
So you saying a strong adharmic India
and a weak dharmic India which is
better. I will say a strong dharmic
India is better.
A strong dharmic India is what we need.
Vssvs says,
"Please ask sir to check Trump's latest
truth social about nations sending
warships to the street of hormones." Oh,
really? Let us see. Okay, let us let us
try and do a Google. Yes, Google search.
Give me a second. Okay,
let us see Trump Truth Social.
So, this is his truth social thing.
What did he say?
I don't want to see a goddamned ads,
Donald Trump.
Okay.
The kind of ads you have on this ish.
Um,
let's see. Many countries, especially
those who are affected by Iran's
attempted closure of the Horbu Strait,
will be sending warships in conjunction
with the US of America to keep the
straight open and safe. we have already
destroyed a 100% of Iran's military
capability where it's easy for them to
send a drone or two, drop a mine or
deliver a close-range missile somewhere
along blah blah blah blah blah no matter
how badly defeated they are. How much
can you lie my friend Donald Trump?
Hopefully China, France, Japan, South
Korea, the UK and others that are
affected by this artificial constraint
will send ships to the area so that the
Hormone Strait will no longer be a
threat by a nation that has been totally
decapitated in the meanwhile. In the
meantime, the US will be bombing the
hell out of the shoreline and
continually shooting Iranian boats and
ships out of the water. One way or the
other, we will soon get this hormone
straight open, safe, and free.
Okay, so that's the thing.
It's just words.
And what else?
Um,
okay. some more
some more complaints about the what he
calls the fake news media.
Um, okay. So, interesting uh
pronouncements by Trump on Truth Social.
He says that Iran has been defeated.
Iran has been totally decapitated. We're
shooting at their boats. But because
they have a few couple of drones and a
couple of mines, that's why the state of
Hormos is closed. That's why he wants
all the nations to send their warships
to open the state of Hormuz. So that
this defeated country can can't keep it
open, can't keep it closed.
His messaging is so incredibly
contradictory. If Iran is so badly
defeated like you claim, why do you need
more countries to send warships there?
Open the street of Hormuz if you're so
powerful and Iran is so defeated. On the
one hand, he's claiming Trump that Iran
is completely defeated and decapitated.
On the other hand, he's asking other
nations to send warships to open the
state of Hormos,
which which obviously means that he
alone that the US alone can't keep it
can't open the state of Hormos.
So, he's making two very contradictory
claims at the same time. One is a claim
and one is an admission.
The claim is that he has defeated Iran.
Iran has lost. Iran is destroyed. Iran
is decapitated. That's the claim he's
making. But he's also admitting that the
US military alone can't keep the state
of Horus open or can't can't open it.
And he needs the support of other
nations.
My god, there is panic.
Trump,
I don't know if it's panic. It's it's
super frustration. And if he's asking
for the help of other nations, it's
close to panic, I would say.
Well, well, well. Yeah. Okay.
Sukoku says you say arad are Indian but
they kill people something same thing
white did to native you don't consider
them American inspired they made America
superpower. What is your question sir?
You have a question here.
You say arian or Indian but they kill
people. Which Arians kill people?
You seem to have this
idea in your mind that white people are
arians, right?
Is that I don't know what you're asking
and what you
I have no idea what you're saying.
Sorry. Next with Rakshit. If India backs
the US, won't we get bit rate again? Of
course we will. Of course.
Uh Roim Querty Roim Querty says, "I
generally watch your videos on Spotify
at 1.5x and your normal pace feels a bit
slow, but thanks for so much. Thanks so
much for all the knowledge you provide."
You're very welcome and please watch at
whatever speed is best for you. A lot of
people say that I speak at 1.5x speed
anyway, but maybe you are a super fast
you have a super fast brain perhaps.
Right, please watch it at whatever speed
is best for you and thank you so much
for being a viewer.
Vssvs says, "Sir Amisha G asks for about
your domain expansion into history
sessions again. From next weekend
onwards, we will do one session on
history and one session on at least one
session on on Iran." Yes. So yeah, I
think we can't just keep having these
sessions only about Iran. From next
weekend onwards we will have one history
session. Okay. And the others can be
about about geopolitics. So yes I your
point is noted Amisha G and that will
resume now. Thank you.
Top seven YT says I'm planning to go to
Dubai to search for a job. Is now the
best time to go given the circumstances?
No. I would recommend to drop your plans
for Dubai at this point in time.
Hopefully the war gets over soon which
is unlikely but if it does then maybe
you can reconsider that but right now
Dubai is not the place to go and right
now the job market in Dubai is going to
be super depressed there will be very
few jobs right now so not a good idea
not a good idea right now
vishnak says namaskar
two questions I I don't really speak
German I understand a few words here and
there I can understand that you're
asking me do I speak German but I don't
speak German. I speak I understand bits
and pieces of various languages. I
understand some German.
I don't really speak German, but if I
read German, I can understand some of
it. Like maybe 15 20% of German, I can
understand. The same applies to many
other languages. Um if I read if I if
there's a page in Spanish, I may
understand 15 20% of it or Italian.
Um yeah. Okay. Now do we lack tinkering
culture in India and are we
geopolitically too altruistic?
Do we lack tinkering culture in India?
We lack a problem-solving culture in
India. We lack
in India, our education system is all
theoretical, right? If you want to get a
degree in engineering, you have to
answer long essay questions and all the
nonsense. If you want to get a degree in
AI, you have to write what are the uses
of AI and long answers. But you if you
want to really get skilled at these
things you have to tinker and we lack
the tinkering culture. You go to IIT and
all do you have tinkering happening
there? No. A little bit maybe but not as
much as you need. So yeah we lack the
tinkering culture in India. The
education system is there's you know put
all the wrong ideas in people's heads.
Are we geopolitically too altruistic?
Yes we are. We need to stop being so
altruistic.
It looks like we are very concerned
about our image.
We want to have this image that we help
everybody in need.
Why? Why?
It's okay to help those who need who are
friendly to you, but don't help the
enemy, right?
Don't help the enemy. So, I think we are
we are geopolitically a little too
altruistic. We are very concerned about
our image to hell with our image.
be a little more hard-nosed is what I
would say. Okay. Shibam Chhataraj says,
"Cood PS4 game has Odin Space Rod
concept in 2013." What's Cood PS4 game?
I am not aware of PS4 game. So, let me
Google that. What is the Cood P4 PS4
game? Let us see what that is. Ros from
from God Concept. Okay, that's
interesting.
Cood PS4. What is Cood? Call of Duty.
Call of Duty. Okay. It has that concept
in 2013. Okay. Very interesting. Thank
you for letting us know. Anabil Sarkcar
says, "Do you think India should get a
huge reserve of ballistic missiles and
chemical drones?" Yes, absolutely.
I think India should have
a big stockpile of maybe 200 300,000
drones
and at least minimum 10 20,000 ballistic
missiles and maybe a few maybe 10 20,000
more cruise missiles of various kinds. A
country of India's size it needs that
sort of stockpile so that nobody dares
to even imagine or dream fighting India.
If we have 5,000 drones and 200
missiles, what's going to be that's
going to run out very soon, right? We
need to have essentially a stockpile
that seems inexhaustible.
We need that.
VSVS says, "My female friend has a crush
on you. She wanted a shout out on her
name is Ria Gupta." Uh, it is not a good
idea to have a crush on me because I am
not available. But hello, Ria Gupta. All
right. Find a good guy and that's all.
All right. Okay.
As says, "Could the Gulf War cause the
AI bubble to pop?" No. No. AI is here to
stay. AI is here to stay. Okay.
AI prod magnet says Iran threatening to
attack US companies in the Gulf. Also,
how is India managing bricks? Iran,
especially Iran after Modi visiting
Israel. Right now bricks doesn't seem to
be at the forefront of our mind
geopolitically.
But as the Iran war goes on and the US
is doing poorly and Iran is doing well,
bricks becomes more important. We'll see
about that about bricks. Anyway, this
year India is the president of bricks,
right? This year it's a rotating
presidency.
Uh so yeah, I think India has learned a
few lessons this the last two weeks. I
mean the leadership of India seems to
have learned a few lessons and a lot of
recalibration has happened in the past
two weeks.
U Iran is threatening to attack US
companies in the Gulf. Yeah. As this
situation escalates, they will attack
everything. They will attack all US
assets in the region. They will do it.
Why not?
They have the capacity to do that. So
they'll do it.
They'll do it if required.
Gotham says, "Are Israeli troops better
trained for ground invasions than US
troops?" I have no idea. There'll be
several YouTubers who have all the
internal insights, all the all the
insights about these things. They will
have sources who have told them
everything.
I have no sources in Israel. I don't
know how well trained Israeli troops
are. There is this mystique about Israel
and this great aura that Israel has that
Israel's troops are the best, Israel's
Moses is the best and so on.
Well,
clearly
it may not be the case, right?
If the Israelis started this war and
dragged the Americans into it
thinking that this war would get over in
a few days, clearly their intelligence
isn't good enough. So, so I don't know
if Israeli troops are better trained
than than US troops for ground
invasions. I don't know.
VSBS says Pawan Gawker
says do you think if India were to
develop all the new technologies if
there were enough invasion of India
would it be more humanentric like
technologies would not be used against
humans
>> India loves talking about human centric
AI humanentric this altruistic AI all
that nonsense understand technologies
are tools and if if
and tools will be used for the worst
things and you have to be prepared for
it.
Now if India were to develop all the new
technologies if there were enough
invasion of India I don't want any
invasion of India I want India to
develop technologies without any
invasion of India
right and if India were to develop
technologies will they be more
humanentric
is India's government humanentric is
India's bureaucracy humanentric are
India's institutions humanentric
the answer is not a very big yes right
answer is kind of not very
So do you think the technologies we will
develop will be also humanentric? I
don't think so. No.
IPK1s says about time we get AC and A IM
podcast has been too long. Well, thank
you for the recommendation.
Okay.
Fast snail says fun thing we have seen
cluster arrows in the Mahabarat war.
Looks like our ancestors thought of a
lot of things.
way before the time for those came
before those things came. Maybe they
were used in the Mabar war was possible.
Yeah. But look today we have cluster
warheads in ballistic missiles. Who
would have imagined?
Prasab Sunni says how do you see the US
as a superpower now and before the war?
They still are a superpower. They still
are the most powerful military in the
world.
But after this war ends
their hard power score is going to
decrease. Their hard power score is
already decreased right now. It was 94
the way I had calculated it may be less
than 90 now. So the power is declining
visibly
visibly.
VSB says do you did you cut off ties
with Aijit Ayar Mitra? Why would I cut
off ties with him? Why?
No of course not. I am on excellent
terms with him.
We meet on and off here and there
wherever. Always by accident.
I Why would I cut off ties with him?
Why? What kind of speculation is that?
Of course not. Of course not.
Shah
Shahar Shar says today JD Vance told he
was against the Iran. He said he was
against the Iran war. Trump
Sir
A North Korea and Japan see ballistic
missiles Mari or China is ready to take
Taiwan. Is this the end of the US
harmony?
Um
okay I'm not aware of what JD Vance
said. Did he say that? Let's let's find
out.
JD Vance Iran
Vance was a skeptical voice in the White
House on Iran strikes. Vance's distance
from the Iran war is getting more
conspicuous.
Um I don't want no prison.
Vice President JD Vance questioned Iran
strike before Trump ordered military
action. Is JD Vance rooting for the Iran
wall to war to fail?
Well, well, well. JD Vance is trying to
throw Trump under the bus now. It looks
like this is politics. It's it's
cutthroat.
So JD Vance is now saying he was against
this war. He was skeptical. I was I did
not I was not in favor of that. So he is
trying to push the blame on Trump and
Trump is trying to push the blame blame
on on Marco Rubio and and his son-in-law
Jared Kushner. Everyone's trying to
point fingers at somebody right now.
Interesting. Very interesting. North
Korea looks like they did some ballistic
missile tests over that region. And
China is is waiting and watching. Okay.
The longer this war goes on, the better
it is for China because the US
weapons stockpiles continue to go down
with every passing day of the war. So is
this the end of the US hedgemony? Not
quite yet. But yeah, the decline is
visible now. The decline has begun.
Yeah, the longer this war goes on, the
the weaker the US dollar will become. A
lot of problems. Lot of problems. This
is the beginning of the actual visible
decline of the US empire. Yes.
Abira Sharkkar says, "Why isn't the US
using Ukraine's drone interceptors?"
Maybe Ukraine drone interceptors.
Ukraine doesn't have drone interceptors.
It has developed ways and means of
of maybe intercepting or targeting
drones,
but I'm not sure if if that can that can
be transposed immediately to the West
Asia war theater. It's not like it's
some technologies that Ukraine has
developed.
When it comes to countering drones, they
use various uh
methods like putting nets and things
like that.
Right. So let's say we know that drones
have in the initial phases of the
Ukraine war targeted tr tanks and all
that. So then what the solution was was
to put up big nets on on poles on top of
of of tanks and put up uh wires and
grids and things so that the drone would
detonate a few feet above the tank and
that will take away most of the damage
that sort of thing. So Ukraine doesn't
have drone interceptors.
It has all these ways and means of doing
things of of of off offsetting the
damage that drones can make
and yeah so it's not that easy otherwise
the US will do it right
manor good to see you we have somehow
done the impossible DRDO has managed to
create indigenous crystal metallergy
that can be used in fifth generation jet
engines baby step for our programs at
least for now hopefully thoughts well
Uh, it's great. It's fantastic. Let's
see.
DRDO crystal methy.
Okay, so DRDO has developed indigenous
single crystal nickelbased super alloy
blade technology for aero engines. That
is outstanding. I mean, what else is
left?
What else is left?
This is outstanding news. This is
outstanding news. And we also the covery
engines after burner has also worked
fine.
I think we are almost there. instead of
purchasing. I mean we should still go
ahead with the relation with the
partnership with Safh to develop an
indigenous Indo-French jet engine but we
should certainly integrate the
um single crystal technology into the
cavary engine and the after murder thing
that's already happened and maybe
maybe induct test the cover engine
properly and see how long it lasts and
all between overholes.
and start inducting that also into into
fighter planes. So I think it's it's
outstanding. It's outstanding despite
all the problems that that you have in
DO and all they're still able to do
this. So it tells you
the potential that we have in India and
I think we should take this forward
definitely. So I think it's it's very
promising. I'm very glad to hear this.
It's it's a ray of sunshine. It's a ray
of hope among all the doom and gloom in
the world right now. So it's great news
overall and thank you for bringing this
to my notice. Arismanticor good to see
you.
As says if India finds huge oil reserves
in the way of Bengal would the US come
for freedom and democracy? If they do
what would happen? The US will try and
create problems for India if oil
reserves are discovered. So what India
needs to do is India needs to massively
strengthen its navy
because there will be big oil reserves
sitting there that that area is known
that region is known to be rich in oil
and gas.
So what India needs to do is to
militarize the area to militarize the
undemand islands and to massively
augment its navy. We should we need to
have 50 more naval ships. We need to
have 50 submarines at least and we need
to have tremendous numbers of missiles,
cruise missiles, anti-ru anti-hship
missiles, drones and everything else. If
you have very very valuable resources,
you need to have the means to defend
those resources. That's what India needs
to do. Then it'll be fine. Then the
Americans will have to stay out.
Otherwise, soon you will have freedom
and democracy coming for you. There is
manticor's project project sundial was
the estimated response from US to Russia
regarding tar bomba but it was so
horrifying that the US military stopped
building it 10,000 megat tons
they may build it again mad or mutually
assured destruction doctrine let's see
project sundial what is that
project sundial
okay let's see what Wikipedia has to say
about It was the sundial was the code
name of one of two massive nuclear bombs
planned for testing by University of
California radif laboratory liver more
branch as part of the classified
Americans weapons project in the early
1950s.
It was intended to have a yield of 10
gigatons of TNT
and its counterpart nom was intended to
have a yield of 1 gaton.
If built and detonated, Sundial would
have created a fireball of up to 50
kilometers in diameter, instantly
igniting everything within 400 km and
causing a magnitude 9 earthquake. That's
madness. Absolute madness. It was
thought the explosion would lead to an
apocalyptic nuclear winter and so on and
so forth. Background blah blah blah. Uh,
okay. Isidor Isaac Rabby, the physicist,
he dismissed the idea as an advertising
stunt. If detonated at an altitude of 28
miles,
it would ignite fires across an area the
size of metropolitan France
and so on and so forth. Okay. Well,
well, well, well, well. One gigaton,
that's uh that's a,000 megatons.
And if you have
uh 10 gatons, that's 10,000 megatons.
You're absolutely right. 10,000
megatons. That's 10 10 gigatons.
Well, that's that's madness. That's that
is absolute madness.
Clearly absolute madness. That that is a
disastrous weapon if you build it. I'm
sure you can make it if you have a
sufficient highly enriched uranium
uranium or plutonium but it's madness.
Um they may build it again but that will
destroy half the world.
magnitude 9 earthquake that's like uh
the Andaman earthquake that you had in
200 whatever four I think or the
Fukushima earthquake senda earthquake
that's that's disastrous
and it will most likely cause a nuclear
winter for the whole world right why why
do that I think it won't be done but uh
crazy they even thought about that
Mantor says keep going we will protect
our sovereignty yes indeed we will
protect our sovereignty no matter what
happens thank Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you for the message of support.
Thank you. Briushi says, "Why Iran
always supports Pakistan on Kashmir
issue? Has Iran ever given money to
Pakistan? Has Iran ever given arms,
ammunition or training to Pakistan? Has
Iran ever helped Pakistan's terrorist
activities? Has Iran ever helped
Pakistan in any
material way?" No. No. No. No. All the
answers to all these questions are no.
Iran has verbally expressed support for
something or the other. Who cares?
Narendra Modi verbally expressed support
for the Israelis and the Americans.
Okay. Done. Doesn't matter. Iran has
never supported Pakistan in any way
whatsoever materially.
That's all that matters.
Fast snails as Israel going after
Lebanon. Good idea at this time. Well,
if they can manage it, go after it. But
let's see. If they think they can
finally defeat Hisbah, go for it. Try it
out. I don't know. I think Hezbollah
also may have a few surprises up their
sleeves perhaps. Uh so I don't know. I
don't know what the situation on the
ground is. How well equipped is Hisbah?
Do they have tens of thousands of
rockets? Possibly. If that's the case,
it will be a disaster for Israel.
Uh so I don't know. I don't know what
Hisbah's capabilities are, what their
secret capabilities are, what they have
kept in reserve.
Right? So since I don't know, I can't
say. But Israel seems to be of the
opinion that it's time to go after
Hezbollah as well while they are
fighting Iran. So if so maybe they have
calculated that it's uh advantageous for
them to do it. So let's see how it goes.
Rohan Bei says, "Russia did not low
Russia did not run low on ammunition in
spite of Ukraine war dragging for years.
US running low on ammunition in that
enabling Chinese takeover of Taiwan.
Taiwan seems unrealistic."
Russia did not run low on ammunition
despite the Ukraine war dragging for
years. Why is that? Because the Russians
have ramped up they've ramped up their
military-industrial complex.
They have these massive factories that
are turnurning out arms, ammunition,
missiles, drones, whatever. And Russia
has inexhaustible resources, raw raw
materials to to build all these finished
products.
Okay. So, Russia has ramped up its its
factories and its military-industrial
complex. That's why the Russians are not
going to run out of anything.
The American
model has been to outsource everything
to outsource all the factory work to
other countries
and their factories are not capable of
churning out ammunition and munitions
and weapon systems and missiles in large
numbers.
So if this war drags on, the Americans
may be forced to ramp up their factories
and stuff, but in America everything
costs a lot of money. In Russia, you can
manufacture a lot of things for cheap
for less money. In the US, everything
costs a lot of money. And if the US
dollar starts declining, then it's going
to become even more expensive.
If the Iranians
succeed in what they're doing, if they
keep the straight of hormones closed, if
they force the Gulf nations to stop
trading for trading
oil for US dollars, it's going to be a
big big big problem for the US. It's
going to start compounding.
Then the US dollar becomes less valuable
and then it's even more expensive to
produce arms, ammunition, weapons,
missiles and so on. So this becomes a
self perpetuating cycle.
So now
uh what what seems unrealistic? What
seems unrealistic? US running low on
ammo. No, it seems realistic. It seems
realistic. And the longer this lasts,
the the the the the
more likely it becomes eventually for
the Chinese to perhaps consider
Taiwan. We'll see. Amisha, good evening,
ma'am. Good to see you. Good to see you.
Uh thanks, sir. You're the best. Thank
you so much, ma'am. I hope the history
sessions re resume soon, eagerly
waiting. You're the only one telling us
truth. Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am. I uh next
weekend onwards, we will have history
sessions once again. I will anyway
continue these geopolitics sessions, the
Iran war sessions because the war is
going on. It doesn't seem to show any
signs of ending soon. But I will resume
the history sessions from next weekend
onwards. All right. Good to see you,
ma'am. Thank you.
Mohit Raj Singh says good morning from
good morning from
NFCA sir YouTube is not allowing
asking question about this war you are
in Canada NF in Canada what is NF in
Canada
oh New Finland really you're in New
Finland
Nice. Nice. New Funland. It's not New
Foundland Land. It's New Funland.
You'll know that only if you if you if
you are in New Finland or if you are in
Canada. For most other people, it's New
Foundland Land. And
so it's New Funland. Hola. I'm glad to
have you from New Funland
and good morning to you and I'm sorry
that YouTube is not allowing you to ask
a question about this war. That's how it
goes sometimes.
Anyway, thank you so much and I'm I'm
glad to see you.
The Mandian says, "Any thoughts on
Gandhiva AI and Nat grid rep that
which triggered SIR?"
Uh, home minister has vowed deportation.
What are the odds and timing
significance of Indian military base
near Siliguri?
I am not aware of what the Gandhiva
either.
I'm not aware of this. I I I keep my
eyes on internal relations, geopolitics.
I don't look into what's happening in
India. I'm usually aware of the contours
of what's happening, but I'm not aware
of the Gandiva AI. Let's see what it is.
Um,
Gandiva AI. What is that?
Cutting edge AIdriven analytics tool
integrated into India's national
intelligence grid. NAT grid. Okay. To
strengthen national security, it links
over 20 critical databases including
financial, telecom and travel data to
provide real-time 360deree profiling of
suspects enabling faster identification
and pattern recognition.
Gandiva excels at facial recognition,
entity resolution, connecting disparate
data points.
um linking bank statements with travel
records in LinkedIn whatever um PAN
cards other GST immigration telecom
records to monitor suspicious
transactions and movements
um etc etc etc
well I'm glad that we have this sort of
thing I hope it's an Indian AI I hope
it's not based on some foreign AI system
I hope it's entirely indigenous and
sovereign sovereign AI and yeah looks
like it's a great tool to have for the
government of India India which will be
great for India's national security.
It'll be great for identifying the
foreign infiltrators who are squatting
in India and then it becomes a polit
policy decision that now that we know
who these foreigners are shall we deport
them or not. So the home minister has
vowed deportation. Well I'm glad that
he's vowed deportation. I now deport
them. I'm glad to hear this a wow. Now
let's see the action.
Yeah, I would I'll be the happiest
person if these illegals are deported at
the earliest.
Yeah. So, I hope it happens.
Significance of Indian military base
near Siliguri should have it. Obviously,
it's significant from the perspective of
safeguarding India's sovereignty and the
security of the region because Siliguri
is this narrow uh patch of land that
connects India. the the the two big
chunks of India, one is the far east of
India, the other is what what is called
the so-called mainland of India. And
Siliguri connects the two. So it's
important that we have you know a strong
military presence in the region. That's
the significance.
Curiosity says was the India Middle East
Europe corridor a joke? Well, it was a
good idea. It was a serious idea. But
the moment it was announced, you had the
October something attack on Israel by
the by Hamas, the horrible terrorist
attack by Hamas on Israel which led to
the Gaza war.
And when Gaza started simmering down now
we have the the war this larger war in
the region and as long as the region is
destabilized you can't you can't have
the IMC because the India Middle East
Europe trade corridor was supposed to
start from Mumbai and western India then
go into the Arabian Peninsula via ports
in Oman etc. And then you'll have rail
lines going through the Arabian desert,
Saudi Arabian desert. Then it will go
into Israel through Hifi from Hifi into
uh Cyprus and then Greece.
But when the whole West Asia region is
destabilized, there's warfare happening
there. You can't have any infrastructure
building over there. You can't have any
trade corridor. So now, right now, it's
it's kind of non-starter.
And yeah, there's problem after problem
that's that's plaguing this this
project. So that is the status right
now. It's kind of kind of become a sad
joke. Hopefully if things are better we
will make this happen.
VSPS says Aush Singh says the Iranian
ship which was sunk by an American
submarine was offered shelter in India
but they chose to be Vasco the Gama.
Why? I have no idea.
Was it offered shelter in India? It was
in India, right? It it it was in I think
Vishakaam or something for a
multinational naval exercise
and then they left and they were sunk
south of Sri Lanka by the American
submarine.
So did India offer it shelter but they
refused it? I'm not sure.
And if they did if if if it's in the
case that India offered shelter but they
chose to leave then I have no idea why
they would have made that choice. I have
no idea but I'm glad that the other two
Iranian ships are safe. One is in Trinum
Mali, the other one is in Koshi, I
believe. So I'm I'm glad those two are
safe.
Goullibar says five of the Nav'i
satellites are completely defunct with
all three atomic clocks in each
satellite not working. Terrible GPS will
be denied in wartime happened in
happened in 1999. Cargill absolutely
it's a disaster and this is I would say
there's no excuse that the that the
government of India can give
to to make this palatable. This is a
horrible failure by the government of
India. It's not like these satellites
failed suddenly.
The it was known that these clocks were
failing.
The atomic clocks are extremely precise
clocks.
Okay.
And they are needed.
Why are they needed? Shall I give you a
physics lesson here? But general
relativity.
Anyway, I'll not give you a physics
lesson here some other time to explain
why these atomic clocks are so
important. But without these atomic
clocks and without without factoring in
the effects of special and general
relativity, you will not have accurate
positioning that given by these
satellites. So these atomic clocks were
failing. This was well known. They're
failing one by one. So why did the
government of India not plan to put out
put up more satellites in time? Now
today we are left without satellite
navigation, indigenous satellite
navigation. If there's a war tomorrow
with Pakistan, the Americans will will
deny GPS to Indian to the Indian
military and we won't have Navik now.
This is a horrible failure by the
government of India.
Unacceptable.
I just don't know. I I have no words to
to express my my indignation and my
outrage.
This
this is not how you safeguard the Indian
national interest.
This is harming the Indian national
interest.
This laxity by the government of India.
Horrible.
E Republic of India says US commander
says the war could trigger Armageddon
while Netanyahu says the Messiah may
come soon. Do you think this conflict is
becoming more of a religious war than a
political one? It looks like there are
religious uh reasons for this. So Trump
was praying to to his God.
There's a bunch of Christian pastors
putting or or Christian church people
um Christian Godmen and women putting
their hands on his shoulders and holding
each other and all that. That was weird.
And uh American commanders at various
levels of the military have been saying
that this is all about Armageddon or
whatever. I don't know. end of the
world. That's what Armageddon means. Why
do you want that? And Natanya is saying
some messiah will come soon. Which which
messiah? Do the Jews have a messiah? I'm
not aware. I don't understand these
religions. So I'm no expert in this. But
clearly looks like there are religious
reasons possibly which may underly
everything that's happening here.
Maybe it's a crusade or maybe it's
something else. I don't know. Looks like
there are other reasons beyond
political, geopolitical, strategic and
military objectives. Maybe there are
some religious objectives these people
have. I don't know what these are. So
yeah, we for balor says how is our
sovereignty status? Right now I am
giving India full sovereign rating.
We'll see after the war. Right now I'll
I'll I'll still give India full
sovereign rating. Obviously
technologically we are not a sovereign
nation with that's very clear. But the
other aspects I will examine in detail
after the war is over. right now I will
give it I will I will list India as one
of the six sovereign nations right now
Shivan Kapoor says I think Iran stay
long good for us what do you say sir
yeah yeah yeah I would like Iran to
remain sovereign that will be good for
us Iran becoming a US fac will be bad
for India I want Iran to remain
sovereign and Iran is doing a great job
of defending its territorial integrity
and its
geopolitical sovereignty. So that is
good for us. I agree with you.
Anonymous says city of London versus
Washington key beef sir. I don't know
about that. A city of London is some
kind of theory that some people have. I
have not studied that so I can't say
can't say I don't know. Sorry. Adity
Chandra says please enlighten us on the
great Israel project and tax Judika and
its relevance in the war. And if
Netanyahu is no more, how will it impact
these Jewish dreams?
So PAX Juda and Greater Israel project
is are these theories that some people
have put out that Israel seeks to be an
expansionist nation and to seek and and
to gain territorial control over the
over a large portion of West Asia. I
think that's what the Greater Israel
Project seems to be. I don't I don't
think Israel has ever officially stated
that it has this these ambitions but of
course there are some things you don't
state right officially
but it's it's speculation okay there is
no off it's not an official thing so
maybe it's there maybe it's not there
maybe the the Israelis maybe they harbor
such hopes but I am not aware of that
judika I think it's the title of some
video by professor Jang or something,
right? I've not seen it. So, I don't
know. I don't know what that could be. I
don't know what that could be. Does it
mean that the Jews will rule the world?
Is that what what it's it's supposed to
be? I don't know. And what's the
relevance of all this in the war? Once
again, if these things are true or not,
if if it's not clear, then I don't know
what the relevance of that in the war
is.
So u these are speculative theories that
may be true but may also not be true and
I generally don't speak about
speculation. I don't speculate about
things so I'll stay out of it. If
Netanyahu is no more, how will it impact
this Jewish dreams?
Well, if hypothetically Netanyahu is no
more, Israel will elect a new leader or
appoint a new leader, the right person
based on merit and then the war
continues. That's how it will go.
And obviously it will be it will be a
setback to Israel because he is their
longest serving prime minister as far as
I know.
Is he Israel's longest serving prime
minister? Let's find out.
Israel longest serving prime minister.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Correct. So he's their
most experienced leader etc. And it'll
be a setback for Israel but I'm sure
that they'll continue no matter what
happens. Aurora says, "Here in the US,
they had a Congress meeting to send
5,000 Marines as six Americans and an
oil tanker were taken down by Iran. But
Iran let an Indian oil tanker go safely.
Is Iran being friendly with India?"
Iran
knows that India is under a lot of
pressure from the US. Iran knows that
India faces significant constraints. But
Iran also knows that India has taken no
steps
that will hurt Iran or harm Iran's
interests. Yes, India India's prime
minister did not offer condolences on
the assassination of Mr. Kame. Yes,
India's prime minister tweeted
uh condemnation of the violation of
sovereignty of the GCC nations and so
on. So indirect criticism of Iran.
But India has taken no actual steps that
will harm Iran. India has not
participated in the American and Israeli
war effort against Iran. India has given
shelter to one Iranian ship in an Indian
port so that the Americans can't destroy
it. So India has actually taken actions
that are you could say that the
Americans could could claim are pro-Iran
and overall India will it will be
beneficial for India. If if Iran
survives and India and Iran have despite
all the American pressure have
maintained a good relationship over the
past decades and Iran seeks to survive
this war and if Iran succeeds in that it
it will be beneficial for Iran to
continue to have good relations with
India. So because of all these factors
the relationship still continues and
Iran is friendly with India and Iran is
allowing Indian tankers to go through
the state of Hormuz. Iran is not
targeting those
and things are going badly for the US.
That's why they're sending 5,000
Marines.
Things are going really poorly for the
US. Right. So yeah,
minimalist Maverick says Trump said
UA war would not have started. Ukraine
war would not have started if he were
the president. What about Iran war? Also
if Iran wins by peace agree by peace
agreement, how would it shape the world
order, UN, etc.? The UN is irrelevant.
Okay. Trump said that Ukraine war would
not have started if he were the
president. Yeah, he he see Trump is a
boastful egotistical person.
He said that the Ukraine war would not
have happened if he were president.
Well, now he he has this Iran war on his
hands that he started
or maybe he was dragged into it by
Israel, but whatever. He started it. So,
yeah, there we have it. Yeah, if Iran
wins
by peace agreement, Iran is not going to
win by a peace agreement. Iran is going
to win by force.
It will shape the world order. It will
reshape the world order. It will
completely alter the balance of power in
West Asia.
Maybe the Syrian government falls soon.
The Syrian government is headed headed
by ISIS terrorist who is a US proteé.
Maybe the if the Iranians eject the the
US from West Asia. Maybe the Syrian
government falls. Who know? That's also
a possibility. Long term,
it will completely reshape the balance
of power in the region. It will be a
huge blow to the American
capacity to project power in the region.
It'll be possibly a huge blow to the US
dollar. So, it's going to completely
reshape the world order. The UN is not
relevant.
Gora TV, good to see you, sir. To
restore its lost reputation, the US may
use tactical nucle nukes on Iran,
possibly after a false flag strike on US
soil. Possible these possibilities are
there. Yes. If that happens, what would
the be the global consequences be? Will
others jump in?
Um there is a possibility, increasing
possibility as the days go by that Trump
will be tempted to use nuclear tactical
nuclear warheads weapons on Iran. Okay,
he he may be tempted to do that. The
thing is even if he uses tactical
nuclear warheads on Iran, Iran will keep
fighting. It will not defeat Iran.
That's the problem for him. He may know
it, but he may not know it. I don't
know. But Iran will keep fighting. It
will not defeat Iran.
What will be the global consequences if
Trump uses nukes?
The global consequences is that other
nations, China, Russia will very
strongly condemn this. And secondly,
other nations may test nukes after that.
Other nations may do nuclear tests
and and
more nations will be tempted to develop
nuclear weapons. those who have the
capability. So yeah, it's going to have
significant consequences of of these
kinds.
Joy Achara says, "Who will control the
world's critical supply chains in in the
next 30 years?"
I think supply chains will be
fragmented.
The way things are going,
I think there could be two parallel
blocks.
One will be the declining Western block.
If the Americans lose this war, the
western block will be declining. And the
other will be the Russian Chinese
Iranian block. India may be possibly
part of it. Yeah,
maybe India will be part of both blocks.
But I think India will have to make a
choice at some point in time.
If the US doesn't win this war, India
India's position will be stronger. It
may be on the bricks camp or something.
So it it remains to be seen. I think the
world's supply chains will be
bifurcated.
There will be two parallel systems
and whoever controls the oil is going to
be in a stronger position
and if Iran doesn't lose this war if
they succeed then then the eastern block
will have control of a majority of the
world's oil. So yeah, cold fire says is
it likely that Trump will lose the
midterms? Very very very likely. Very
likely.
VSVS says what's your opinion on the
youth of this country? dedic dedicating
their life to Galgotia University.
The youth of the country dedicating
their life to Golgotia University. I am
not aware of this development. When did
the youth decide this?
I have not seen any youth dedicating his
or her life to this university. But um I
am not aware of this development. Is it
supposed to be a joke questions? I mean
I don't know. Yeah, I I'm not aware of
this development. Sorry. Which is this
university? Galgotia. Is it the one with
the fake Chinese robot?
Okay. Sin Pervine says, "Did the US or
Israel use some kind of tactical nuke on
Iran's comm region? Saw some videos in
Twitter a few days ago claiming it was
some kind of nuke." I don't know if it
was a nuke or not. I mean, if you see
that explosion,
give me a second.
Uh,
let me try and dig it out.
Where do we have it?
Okay, so here's the thing.
Here's the tweet.
I am not a big fan of this account. So,
I'm just putting it out here because the
tweet is there. So, let me mute that and
play it.
Mute that. So, the video starts.
>> Come on. The video starts when the
explosion is already mature. Okay? See,
if the video starts at the moment of the
explosion, then it's easier to determine
whether it's a nuke or not because
there's a double double flash. This
characteristic signature of a nuclear
explosion is a double flash. But here we
start.
>> If you
the mushroom cloud is nearly 2
kilometers high and we have these
characteristic tendrils over here that
are characteristic of nuclear
detonations.
So this is a very suspicious thing over
here. And even the mother of all bombs,
the MOABs that the Americans have, it
does not produce a a mushroom cloud like
this. This looks very suspiciously like
a tactical nuclear explosion.
And it may look small or it may not be
able to see how big it is, but we know
where this explosion happened. We know
the size of that hill that you see in
this image. And that hill is about 300 m
high.
If the hill is 300 m high, it means that
this mushroom cloud is about 2
kilometers high at this point in time. 2
km
a regular weapon doesn't produce a
mushroom cloud of that height. Even the
mother of all bombs that the Americans
have, the largest non-nuclear weapon, it
doesn't produce a mushroom cloud with
those characteristics.
So it looks very suspiciously like a
tactical nuclear explosion, but the
Iranian government has said the thing
about it. If it was a really it was if
it was really a nuke, they would have
complained about it, right? The Iranian
government. So I don't know. It's very
suspicious.
I can't say for sure that it is a nuke,
but I can't say for sure it's not a
nuke. That's the point.
Aries Manticor says on an honest note
while we are pragmatic we are still
behaving in the same optics liberal voke
mindset which with the talks like about
humanentric tech we need someone to tell
them to recalibrate their approach the
government of India when it comes to AI
talks about humanentric blah blah blah
we need to have a hardnosed approach to
AI AI is a tool it's a weapon
everybody is weaponing AI but we are
everybody is weaponizing AI every see
the US military is using AI systems to
choose targets and kill targets and
that's how they ended up killing those
200 school girls or 180 school girls
because they allowed AI to choose a
target. AI is being used in war
and in India we're talking about
humanentric AI and equitable AI and blah
blah blah. The whole world is
weaponizing it and we are talking about
nonviolent Gandhian use of AI.
I am okay. AI should be used equitably
with a nonviolent approach and human
approach and all but when the whole
world is using it for for for warfare
you also must develop your capability to
use AI for warfare
and when you apply to the civilian
domain use it for humanentric approach
or whatever but India is only about
humanentric approach
stupidity.
Ammon Kubar Dankar says, "Seems missiles
and drones can dwarf naval ships. They
can destroy naval ships. Missiles and
drones can take out entire aircraft
carriers, which is why the American
aircraft carriers are far away from the
war. They're sitting far away from the
from the range. They're still probably
within range of Iranian ballistic
missiles, but they're
trying to keep as far away as possible."
Aurora says, "I read that the Indian
continent was part of Africa and
Americas a few million years ago. When
do you think we emerged? Did we have
some species some kind of species that
originated from India?
So we have something called te tectonic
drift on the planet. Okay. Uh see if you
look at let's let's Google this a
cross-section of the earth. So we have
magma and other stuff in the inside the
earth. The inside of the earth is molten
and there's a solid core.
Crosssectional diagram of the earth
uh internal structure of the earth. So
as you can see the out the solid surface
that we are aware of that's just the the
crust of the earth. It's a very thin
layer. Inside you have a lower crust.
Then h come on man this is not a good
one.
So you have a mantle then you have the
magma layer. Okay. The lithosphere is
solid. Then you have magma layer which
is lava and then at the at the center
you have the core which is solid. So
because the surface of the earth is the
solid crust which is floating on liquid
magma
that's why this the surface of the earth
it keeps shifting and drifting over time
which is called tectonic activity.
And you have these plates tectonic
plates that drift around that collide
which causes earthquakes and which slide
on top of each other and come down and
and so on. So because of this about 50
million years ago India which was
originally attached to Africa it broke
up from Africa not 50 million years ago
it happened maybe 70 million years ago
and about 66 million years ago India the
India was an island in the middle of the
Indian Ocean. It was on top of the Raino
hotspot
66 million years ago. That's why we had
tremendous volcanism in India. The
Deckan traps and India started colliding
with the Eurasian continent about 30 or
so million years ago. So it was a very
slow process obviously millions of years
and that's why the Himalayas were formed
and that's why you have fish fossils
thousands of meters up in the Himalayas.
So India was part of the was part of
Africa. Now we can still see the shapes
you know if you go to the map. Okay. If
you see the shape of India and
Madagascar etc. you will see that they
all fit together.
So see the shape of India. See the shape
of Madagascar.
It's like a jigsaw puzzle piece which
can fit over here. Right?
And
badasar also was attached to Africa. You
can still see the shapes. Right?
So yeah and if we look at terrain if you
look at the bottom of the ocean okay you
will see the ridge lines etc which which
you can see some of it was caused by
India moving all the way out.
So yeah that is indeed the case. India
was attached to Africa long ago and
because of tectonic drift India moved
away and slammed into Asia into Eurasia
which is what pushed up the Himalayas
which are still growing. The collision
is still happening.
Um so that's what happened. You had
dinosaur species in India which
originally may have been native to
Africa and then the dinosaurs well the
non-avian dinosaurs died out. The a the
aven dinosaurs are still around. I saw
some just now. I mean, I saw some aven
dinosaurs just a few hours ago.
Hyphen says, "I think most people don't
know, but UK is already involved in the
war since day two. The US is using
British air bases and so much more."
Absolutely. The UK is involved.
The US is using British air bases
as pit stops and refueling stops and so
on in this war against Iran. Yeah,
absolutely. The UK is involved.
Ashish says, "If the US fights a direct
war with India with boots on Indian
soil, will it end US hijgemony? Explain
how. I know they will not do this. But
what if hypothetically?
If the US fights a direct war with
India, given India's current military
capabilities, India will lose. India
doesn't have the mountains all across
its the subcontinent that will prevent
the Americans from making big inroads
quickly.
India doesn't have a stockpile of
hundreds of thousands of drones and tens
of thousands of missiles. That will be a
disaster for the US. India doesn't have
any of that. India spends about 2% of
its GDP on its military and a lot of
that goes into pensions and salaries.
India is not a nation that's that's
geared to fight a long war. India
imports more than 50% of its military
equipment from other countries including
the US. If the US launches an invasion,
hypothetical invasion of India, India
will lose very badly.
India will lose very very badly.
Yeah.
So the the moral of the story is
get prepared.
Stockpile hundreds of thousands of
drones and tens of thousands of missiles
of different kinds. Militarize.
In that case the story will be
completely different. But right now we
don't even have satellite navigation.
Our government has been sleeping
sleeping.
What can I say? Ankur says if you were
managing a global macro hedge fund what
geopolitical signals would you track
weekly and thank you for all the
knowledge. Well if I was managing a
global macro hedge fund
um what would I track weekly? I don't I
am not an e economics guy. I what
geopolitical signals I would what
geopolitical signals would I track? I
would look for
inflection points which is like very
immediate urgent stuff. Inflection
points. I would look for
I would look for shadow signals.
Shadow signals are like small
insignificant pieces of news that
typically get buried in the news. be
page three, page five, whatever. But if
you know how to look for shadow signals,
they have the potential to turn into
inflection points 6 months, 1 year, 2
years down the line. Things that look
inconspicuous,
but that they become very big eventually
if you know what to look for. And there
are some telltale characteristic
signatures of shadow signals that that
tell you that these could be important
data points.
H uh what else would I look for? I would
look for the pulse of the global
economy. All those that you can get from
the Bloomberg terminal or whatever that
sort of thing.
Uh but what I would really look for
would be shadow signals.
That's what I would do.
you know, things that are leading
indicators of of of
future inflection points. That's what I
would look for.
Okay. Empty box says, "Heard your
ancestors protected Somnat." Can you
tell more?
My ancestors protected Somnat. Yes, they
did. That was a very long time ago, more
than a thousand years ago.
uh there is something called the Chavda
dynasty that ruled over that part of
India and uh since they were the rulers
of western India not western Gujarat
present day Gujarat Snath came under
their protection right
they were the guardians and protectors
and servants of the great jotir linga of
sunnath
so yeah my ancestors did
uh perform that role for about two and a
half centuries. Yes,
Fields Strong Band says, "I would love
to play a game, a full game of
Civilization 6 with you in the distant
future." Basically, building our country
through geopolitics, diplomacy, trade,
war, etc. as video game. I've heard of
this game. I know some very intelligent
people who play this game. Let's see
what it looks like. I've seen Yeah.
Civilization 6.
Yeah, this game I I've never played it,
but I'm pretty sure it's a fascinating
game. You you essentially build your own
country, your own your own empire, your
own kingdom and empire and civilization,
etc. And it's a game of strategy,
long-term strategy, and so much more. I
think it's a very interesting game.
Yeah, maybe we'll one day we'll play it.
Let's see. Okay. Astrophysics short
videos says, "What are your views on
Heen Shellar astrophysics book?"
Astrophysicist book hyperrelativity. I
am not aware of this uh book and this
astrophysicist so I don't have any views
hyper relativity really um I'm not aware
of it
hyper relativity
what is this
uh
it's a book by Shellar I am not aware of
this book
I have no idea
um no I am not aware so I can't say a
thing about it obviously I've not read
it. I'm not aware of it. McLevin says
best time for RA and free the east from
the west. Russia, India, China. Well,
maybe maybe R could not be maybe RS
could happen. Yeah, the way things are
going, maybe it'll be it'll be a good
thing for India and and and the world.
Yeah.
Phoneography says, why didn't you call
Iran sovereign before? No nukes. One
thing is no nukes. The other thing is
that is that it was very very dependent
on China and Russia for so many things
but after the war started they have been
fighting on their own without direct
assistance from China or Russia.
There is obviously some indirect
assistance and so on you know BU and so
on so forth but overall they're fighting
on their own. There's no Russian
supplies or Chinese supplies coming in.
So clearly they're defending their
sovereignty and they are acting as a
completely sovereign nation and that's
why I have added them to the list of
sovereign nations. They completely
deserve that.
Vir Kapper says, "Iran leaders FM often
stand out globally smart, charismatic
and active even in old age. Many envy a
culture that looks inward to its gods
and good couple life.
Iran has very good diplomats and good
leadership."
Yes, I I agree. Yes.
Right. Okay. VSVS says, "Sir, have you
ever watched Suits? I personally loved
the show." I personally haven't watched
it in great detail. I know somebody who
used to be a big fan of the show
and uh I think it's a very interesting
show. At least the first few seasons, if
I recall correctly,
I may perhaps have seen an episode or
two.
It used to be a great show. Eventually,
it did, as all shows typically go, it
started meandering.
Uh, but yes, I've seen a couple of
episodes, I'm sure, at some point in
time, many years ago, and I think it was
a very smart, very intelligent, and very
interesting show. Yeah, but yeah, I
haven't seen the whole thing. Maybe a
couple of episodes.
Har what? Harvey. Okay, I forget. Harvey
Spectre, I think that's that's the main
guy's name. All right. V for valor says
out of badach and chachore why to choose
you should not choose any chore yeah but
I'm not sure what you're saying but all
right
vid singh says go sleep yeah I look
forward to sleeping if these questions I
I need to finish the remaining super
chats and then I shall sleep it's been
more than 4 hours 22 minutes a very long
session it's pretty late here it's
really late so thank you I look forward
to sleeping xzp is a new member welcome
to the channel's membership thank you so
much before becoming a member. Ramen Gil
says, "Do you think Israel will use
India to knock out Pakistan as that's
the last straw with nukes after former
prime minister of Israel says Turkey is
the new Iran?"
I don't think so.
See, I'll tell you why.
Pakistan is an American vasal state.
It's an American asset. The United
States has supported Pakistan for
decades.
The US has funded and financed Pakistani
terrorism against India historically.
That is a known fact. Even the Americans
can't deny this.
Most likely Pakistani nukes are actually
American nukes. I don't
believe for one second that Pakistani
engineers and scientists have the
capability to develop nuclear weapons on
their own. These nuclear warheads they
have are most likely American nuclear
warheads placed in Pakistan and they are
most likely controlled only by Americans
not by Pakistanis.
So if that is so that is one and
Pakistan is an American asset. Now
America's number one ally and partner is
Israel and America's vasal is Pakistan.
So the question is what is the
relationship between Israel and
Pakistan? Most like see Pakistan doesn't
recognize Israel officially
and there are no diplomatic relations
between the two two countries
but when aimun went to Washington or
wherever and the Pakistani embassy held
a reception for him there was an Israeli
military presence there so most likely
there is a hidden relationship between
Israel and Pakistan
and most likely they are kind of on the
same side now I'm not trying to say that
Israel is India's enemy I'm not saying
that but Israel has its own independent
relationship with Pakistan and it's a
secret relationship most likely
and most likely it's a relationship
that's good for Israel.
So why will Israel knock out Pakistan?
They won't. Most likely Pakistan is in
some shape or form
acceptable to Pak to Israel.
Yeah,
Shivam says, "Thoughts on Claude's fight
with Pentagon?" Yeah, CL Yeah, Claude
doesn't the Claude leadership doesn't
want the Pentagon to use Claude to kill
people. They want guardrails and so on.
And Pentagon says, "No, we will use it
whichever way we we want." So that's why
there's a rift between the Pentagon and
Claude. And that's why the Pentagon is
going to go open ahead go ahead with
open AI instead of claude and pent and
and claude and anthropic will you will
lose the contract which is what 200 to
$300 million which is penis from their
perspective because their revenue is so
big.
Uh so yeah and apparently claude was
used for targeting
targets selecting targets during the
current war against Iran
which has led to horrific circumstance
consequences as we know targeting a
school that sort of thing possibly.
Mohit Raj Singh says is Russia benefit
from
is Russia benefit from it and vapes
to build themselves like USSR and can
Russia China help openly if Iran falls
or get nuked like us? What is
does Russia benefit from it? From what
and vapes
to build themselves like USSR and can
Russia China help openly if Iran falls
or get nuked like US have its puppets?
Okay. If Iran is in deep trouble, Russia
and China will openly help it. Okay.
Yes. Most likely Russia and China will
both openly help it. Russia more than
China because Russia is geographically
closer to Iran. If you see the see the
map. Okay, let's open the map. Let me
show you quickly. If you open the map,
you will see that Russia and Iran are
not far away. Just north of the Caspian
Sea, you have Russia. The Sea of Kashup,
Thean, North of Thran, you have the
Caspian Sea. In north of the Caspian
Sea, you have Russia. So, Russia is not
there far away that far away. Uh what do
I do? Okay, so that's a deal. So Russia
can definitely help Iran if required.
Okay, if Iran is in trouble, even the
Chinese will help in some shape or form.
Now the question you're asking is does
Russia benefit from it from the war?
Yeah, it does. It does because now
Russian oil is very valuable. You see,
that's why the whole world seeks Russian
oil. India also seeks Russian oil right
now and that's why Russian oil is now
being sold at a premium even for India.
Earlier it was sold to India at a
discount. Now it's at a it's at a
premium. Hersh Weren says atomic clock
crisis in Navic satellites of ISRO
views. I expressed my views in detail.
It's a disaster. It is unacceptable that
the government of India was sleeping on
the job. It's unacceptable that we have
not sent set sent replacement
satellites. Yes, we had the PSLV
failures and all. Deal with it. Fix the
problem. Address the issue. identify the
issue and fix it. It's unacceptable that
we don't have satellite navigation
anymore. This you could have seen coming
from years ahead.
The government of India has dropped the
ball completely when it comes to India
space program. And this is a strategic
disaster for India. I don't know when
the next satellites go up. India is a
low ambition nation when it comes to
space. We have a local regional
satellite constellation and that too has
failed now and it's failed because it's
become too old.
It's a this is a it's a sad joke sad
joke. It's extremely frustrating and I
blame nothing nobody but the government
of India for this. They have this is a
huge failure. They have failed to do the
job.
You can't blame Neo for this.
The government of India can't blame Neu
for what's happened here. Now
Barat says what are some highquality
news sources online and X? Uh no no
I don't follow any one source. I look at
hundreds of sources.
Um
X uh I look at everybody on X. All the
major accounts that are twe tweeting
about something. I don't know any high
quality single news source. Sorry VSVS
says Spider-Man Abijit he does many
other things too. He is the purest
definition of clown.
He does many other things too. He is a
purest definition of clown. Don't get
fooled by his fake generosity.
I have seen jokers like him. He is a
zero self-respect bootlicker of anyone
he thinks.
G comments on me. I have no idea what
this is about.
Who is the purest definition of clown?
Who is who has fake generosity?
Zero self-respect bootlicker of anyone
who thinks
g comments on I have no idea what this
is, but okay. Is it is somebody
referring to me? I have no idea. Sorry,
I don't speculate. I don't know what
this is about. Okay, Jimmy Lee says,
"The game Hearts of Iron 4 is
interesting as well." Hearts of Iron 4.
Let's quickly take a look. What's Hearts
of Iron 4?
Hearts of Iron 4.
What is that? Hearts of Iron Form. It's
It's on Steam.
It's a grand strategy video game
developed by Paradox Development Studio,
published by Paradox Interactive,
and so on. It's a grand strategy war
game. It focuses on World War II. Very
interesting. Players can control any
country in the world and so on.
Interesting. Interesting. Thank you.
Samuel Kings has gifted one membership
of the channel. Thank you very much,
sir. Very kind of you. Very kind of you.
Thank you. Samuel King says, "I am from
the US. There are news. There's news
that BB Netanyahu is dead. Not
officially confirmed, but knowing how
the Israelis are heavily censoring
things." Yes, I remarked upon this at
the very beginning of this live stream 4
and a half hours ago that that there are
indications very
serious indications that something may
have happened to him. The most important
indication is this deleted tweet from
the official account of the prime
minister of Israel, right? In which they
are essentially admitting that they they
they have lost contact with Netanyahu.
So this came out about 24 hours ago then
it was quickly deleted.
This
raises big questions about what has
happened to Netanyahu. So it's obviously
not officially confirmed but yeah. Yeah.
The Israelis are obviously censoring
things. It's it's war time so they will
censor information. Yeah. Gesh says how
can the US win war? How can USA win war
with USA unethical? Yes. How can you
war? How can USA win war with USA?
I don't even know what the question
means, sir. How can India win a war with
India? How does it work? What are you
asking? Not sure.
Okay. Vsv says, "Sir, Spider-Man G is
talking about me, sir. Calling me a
clown." Oh, he's calling you a clown.
Why? Why? Why? I think VSVS, you're
doing such an such a good job. You're
being very kind to people who want to
ask questions but who maybe students or
whatever they can't take super chats.
You're being very kind to them and
you're asking questions on their behalf.
Why is somebody calling you a clown?
Why? I don't get it. Anyway, yes, I
appreciate you. Thank you for for what
you're doing.
Ashtik says, "Are chemtrails real? Can
we do anything about it?"
I don't know if they're real. Obviously,
we have the contrails that we see of
aircraft. I've been seeing that since I
was a little toddler. You know, look out
in the sky and there's these long
contrails and I I used to wonder what
they were about. But that that that
comes from the condensation
of water
that's ejected out of jet engines as
part of the exhaust and that condenses
and that produces this cloud these long
contrails. And uh some people said that
these are chem trays that chemicals are
being spread in that. And is it true? I
have no idea. That's considered to
possibly be a conspiracy theory. And
there clearly is no hard evidence of it.
But theoretically, it's possible that
there could be something behind it, but
I don't know. I'm I don't have the
information. I don't know. Bua says,
"What's the meaning of life?" Well, I
don't know. I don't know what's the
meaning of life.
The meaning of life, meaning and purpose
are different things. What's the
meaning? Well, it's a mystery. We are
still trying to find out what is the
meaning of life. But what I'll say is
that life exists and let's make the best
of it. Enjoy life as much as possible
and and create something of value and
make it as meaningful as possible. So I
suppose meaning
depends on who you are. For me, meaning
will be different. For somebody else,
meaning will be something else.
Whatever makes your life meaningful and
worth living is the meaning of life. And
for two different people, it will be two
different things, I'm sure. But yeah,
it's up to you.
Okay. Gamer gamer Pravin says, "Your
thoughts on the global firepower index."
I haven't seen that, so
I don't know. No, no, sorry. Bona graphi
says, "How to email you to explain
Zionist Christian worldview."
Uh, my email ID will be there in the
description.
You can email me and I'll try to take a
look at that. But I can't promise you in
response because I get so many emails
every day and I simply if I start
responding to all the emails I that's
all I'll be doing and even then I won't
be able to respond to everybody. So
yeah, please feel free to email me in
the email address given in the
description below. All right. All right.
I think that's the end of the questions
for today. It's been more than 4 and a
half hours. So,
so yeah, that brings me to the end of
today's live stream. Thank you so much
everybody. I think there's more
questions coming up now.
How the US can defeat India unethically?
Yes, the US can defeat India. It's very
powerful. Through firepower and through
economic means and other means, it can.
And Anaj, thank you very much. An Baj,
thank you. And that finally brings me to
the end of this live stream. More than
four and a half hours. It's past
midnight in India. So I shall now end
this live stream. Thank you so much
everybody. Keep asking questions. Ke
raising your standards. Keep learning
and I take care of yourselves and I'll
see you in the next one very soon. Take
care for now. Good night. Goodbye. Good
day. Boy.